<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>paul.j.fenwick</title>
		<description>Some guy from the internet who loves freedom.</description>
		<link>http://pjf.id.au/</link>
		<atom:link href="http://pjf.id.au//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Use Markdown Instead Of BBCode With Vimperator</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I really love the Dwarf Fortress community, and a lot of it is centred around the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bay12forums.com/smf/index.php&quot;&gt;bay12 forums&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, I don’t love BBCode (aka phpBB syntax), which is what the bay12 forums require me to write posts in. I’d much rather use &lt;a href=&quot;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax&quot;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt;. So I decided to fix that with the help of vimperator, and by writing my own markdown to BBcode parser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you install the &lt;a href=&quot;https://metacpan.org/pod/Markdown::phpBB&quot;&gt;Markdown::phpBB&lt;/a&gt; module from the CPAN, you’ll find a nifty little program named &lt;code&gt;md2phpbb&lt;/code&gt;. This is a filter; it takes input in markdown, and emits output in BBcode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cpanm Markdown::phpBB     # install using cpanm
$ cpan  Markdown::phpBB     # install using classic cpan&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re editing in vim, you can run &lt;code&gt;:%!md2phpbb&lt;/code&gt; to replace your current buffer (written in markdown) with the equivalent text in BBcode. You can even bind it to a key, as I’ve done in my &lt;code&gt;~/.vimrc&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;:nmap &amp;lt;F5&amp;gt; :%!md2phpbb&amp;lt;CR&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve installed md2phpbb into a user (rather than system) directory, then you may find that vimperator won’t have your perl-specific environment variables in place. In that case you can use full paths in your &lt;code&gt;~/.vimrc&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;:nmap &amp;lt;F5&amp;gt; :%!perl -I/home/pjf/perl5/lib/perl5 /home/pjf/perl5/bin/md2phpbb&amp;lt;CR&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vimperator.org/vimperator&quot;&gt;vimperator&lt;/a&gt; then you can already invoke vim from any textarea by pressing &lt;code&gt;ctrl-i&lt;/code&gt;. However BBcode websites usually bind this to &lt;em&gt;italics&lt;/em&gt;, so you’ll probably want to add an additional key for editing to your &lt;code&gt;~/.vimperatorrc&lt;/code&gt; file. I use &lt;code&gt;ctrl-e&lt;/code&gt;, for edit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;:inoremap &amp;lt;C-e&amp;gt; &amp;lt;C-i&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can use &lt;code&gt;ctrl-e&lt;/code&gt; to open a vim window, write your response in markdown, and then just hit &lt;code&gt;F5&lt;/code&gt; to turn it into BBCode. Best of all, the filter doesn’t change existing BBCode at all, so you can hit &lt;code&gt;F5&lt;/code&gt; as many times as you like, to refresh your text after edits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;md2phpbb&lt;/code&gt; and supporting libraries are completely free and open source, and can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjf/Markdown-phpBB&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also: &lt;a href=&quot;http://privacygeek.blogspot.com.au/2013/03/the-worlds-easiest-guide-to-installing.html&quot;&gt;The world’s easiest guide to installing cpanm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au///tech/2014/01/16/use-markdown-rather-than-bbcode-with-vimperator.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au///tech/2014/01/16/use-markdown-rather-than-bbcode-with-vimperator.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                     

                     

                     

                     

                     

                     

                     

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Depression—An Update</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In late 2012 I had a depressive episode. This is well documented; &lt;a href=&quot;2012-11-29-i-have-depression-an-open-letter-by-paul-fenwick.html&quot;&gt;I wrote about it on-line&lt;/a&gt;, and I even &lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/talks/2013/07/24/depression-bugs-in-your-brain.html&quot;&gt;gave a talk at OSCON&lt;/a&gt;. My thought processes during that time were broken and cyclical; cognitively I knew that people were great, but emotionally I found myself intensely disliking them. As someone who’s long derived joy and energy from those around me, I seemed to spend all my energy arguing with the emotional part of myself that people &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; great… and yet it wouldn’t listen. The situation was exhausting, and I didn’t get anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I struck a deal. I would admit that perhaps people aren’t as great as I once thought, and that emotional monkey-brain would quieten down and let me think again. It worked, and I’d joke with my role-playing friends I recovered by taking a point in misanthropy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a good deal, because I knew that point in misanthropy could eventually be removed, and because &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; was better than being in the state I was back then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the misanthropy stuck around. It’s not as bad as it used to be, but it’s definitely there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have noticed me at less events in 2013, and part of that’s because the thought of seeing people has often been completely unappealing. Usually when I’m at an event, I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; social and happy, but the misanthropy often comes back as soon as I leave. Sometimes it comes back hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans have a knack of making up plausible excuses for our own behaviour, and then believing those excuses to be real¹. We have the same knack when it comes to emotions. We’ll look for things in our environment try to explain why we’re feeling a particular way, and believe they’re &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; the reason we feel that way².&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, when I’m feeling misanthropic, it’s hard for me to tell which thoughts of mine are actually legitimate, and which thoughts only &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; legitimate because of my emotional state. Often I’m appalled when I look back at some of my thoughts when I feel this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Readers of &lt;a href=&quot;http://hpmor.com/&quot;&gt;HPMOR&lt;/a&gt; will be familiar with assigning labels to the different viewpoints in one’s own head. When I’m feeling misanthropic, my Slytherin brain seems to get a larger share of my think-space. Slytherin brain isn’t evil; instead it’s rational, ethical, and often it pairs up with Ravenclaw brain to provide strong empirical support for its arguments. Slytherin brain is strongly oriented towards achievements and problem-solving; it’s often the reason &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; I get stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However Slytherin brain has a reduced coefficient-of-concern—not only for others—but also for my own short-term circumstances. It’s acceptable for myself—or other people—to suffer short-term discomfort if it results in long term good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m in a peaceful, stable state, Slytherin brain gives great advice. It means I’ll pass on the thing which seems attractive now, but which I know will prove to be a bad choice later on. It’s why I’ll do boring but essential paperwork when I could be looking at pictures of cats on the Internet. Slytherin brain wields executive function like a boss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However when I’m misanthropic, Slytherin brain presents all sorts of plans to make &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; feel better, but which almost completely ignore the feelings of others. While it acknowledges that being a total jerk isn’t going to make anyone happy, it seem to feel I could be a &lt;em&gt;lot more&lt;/em&gt; of a jerk to get what I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not exactly happy with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’m primarily writing this to help quell my thoughts, I’m certainly not above help and assistance. If you do wish to lend a hand, then please encourage me to get out, get involved, and don’t hesitate to introduce me to others face-to-face. I have a good inclination that with enough exposure to fabulous people my misanthropy will reduce. I hope this year I’ll be able to kick it for good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¹ Bargh, John A., and Tanya L. Chartrand. “The Unbearable Automaticity of Being.” American Psychologist 54, no. 7 (1999): 462–479. doi:10.1037/0003-066X.54.7.462.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;² Amongst other things, my talk ”&lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/talks/2011/07/29/all-your-brains-suck.html&quot;&gt;All Your Brains Suck&lt;/a&gt;” discusses how we use environmental queues to rationalise thoughts and emotions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au///depression/2014/01/02/personal-depression-an-update.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au///depression/2014/01/02/personal-depression-an-update.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>On Open Source Software And Communities</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Open source software is great. You don’t have to worry about the owner deciding to discontinue it, because someone else can always take over. If there’s a bug that really annoys you—or a feature you really want—you can add it. If you’re concerned about what the software might be doing, you can open it up and take a look. And even if you don’t have the skills or inclination to do all these things, other people will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’ve always known open source software is great, I’m increasingly starting to appreciate that open source &lt;em&gt;developers&lt;/em&gt; are also great. Many people in open source not only have a tremendous amount of experience with software, but also community management. They’ve seen a lot of the same problems arise many times, and so they have a good idea on how to get code, and people, to work together productively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that we see, again and again, in both software and the community, is that giving people agency and discretion is fundamental in having a highly successful project. Wikis lowered the barrier to contribution immensely when it came to collating knowledge, Wikipedia wouldn’t exist if it wasn’t so easy to edit. Many of the most successful software projects have been extremely generous with their commit bits, and with distributed version control, the barriers to contribution have been lowered even further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason this is so essential for success is simple. The vast majority of intelligent, motivated people &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to make the world a better place; putting barriers in their way simply means they’ll go elsewhere. Every permission form that needs to be filled in, every registration process that needs to be jumped through, every legal framework that encumbers creation, every strict power hierarchy that needs to be worked through, they all run the risk of taking someone who may done something great instead deciding it was “too hard”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say that we won’t need a way to deal with mishaps; even if nobody is malevolent, some people will still be learning, and everyone will make mistakes. Wikis and distributed version control strike a good balance here, they’re designed around the ability to undo changes, or revert to previous revisions if need be. Much of the software that lower the barriers to contribution also lower the risks associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s the key here. If you can give people a way of doing something, and that process comes with low or negligible risks, then &lt;em&gt;let them do it&lt;/em&gt;. Even if you think nobody will care, even if you think it’s a terrible idea, &lt;em&gt;let them&lt;/em&gt;. Many great ideas start as terrible ones that are refined over time, and you may be surprised at just how popular some ideas can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this doesn’t just apply to your software, or your documentation; this applies to the your culture, and the society in which you live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encourage others to be bold. Be generous in what you accept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not stifle innovation. Do not get in the way of people being great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I know that sometimes it can feel like two steps forward, and one step back; but please, please, don’t stop contributing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au///ethics/2013/12/28/on-open-source-software-and-communities.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au///ethics/2013/12/28/on-open-source-software-and-communities.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Admission: I'm a hypocrite</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’m going to admit something awful. I’m a hypocrite. I don’t try to hide that. I advocate using one’s resources to make the world a better place, and yet I do a poor job of that myself. I think that raising animals for food is wrong, and yet I still eat meat. I cannot justify these actions in any way that I feel comfortable about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And really, that’s the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be simple for me to find a reason why I don’t care about the suffering of others. Overpopulation is an easy excuse, and it’s one I’ve reached for in the past. There are an endless number of excuses I can reach for to justify eating meat. I have no doubt that I could make a show of defending these positions if I chose to take them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However if I give myself excuses, then I &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; hide behind them. And if I believe my own excuses, then I won’t even &lt;em&gt;try&lt;/em&gt; to change my behaviour. What’s worse, I may even try to justify the behaviour of others who adopt the same behaviour as myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the stigma associated with being a hypocrite, and despite the cognitive dissonance it causes, being a hypocrite provides me with something very valuable: it still allows me to improve myself, and the world, for the better. That social and mental discomfort pushes me towards more ethical choices, and it allows me to support others who are improving in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you really want me to challenge your beliefs, then I will, but I would rather welcome you to join me in my hypocrisy. Admit that the suffering of others &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; important—on a global scale—but that we both personally have a lot left to be done to improve our own responses to that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was originally made as a comment on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/paul.fenwick/posts/10151875254259611&quot;&gt;another thread regarding ethics&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve posted it here—with minor edits—for a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au///ethics/2013/12/16/im-a-hypocrite.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au///ethics/2013/12/16/im-a-hypocrite.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>The ethics of everyday people</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I seem to regularly find myself horrified by the ethics of everyday people. That’s not to say that most people are bad, but we adopt the ethics of the society in which we’re raised, and very few people think about things in any other way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are concerned with what happens nearby, both geographically and temporally. So many of our thoughts are about what happens in our suburb, our country, our circle of friends, our lifetimes. There’s less care for those who live far away, and almost no thought for people living 10,000 years from now. That’s odd if we claim that we care about the welfare of others, because there are &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; people living far away, and &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; people living in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What goes hand-in-hand with this is a tendency to discount any sort of change that doesn’t affect the here-and-now. Hurricane Katrina saw almost &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2005/09/08/AR2005090801081.html&quot; title=&quot;Washington Post: Congress approves $51.8 Billion for Victims&quot;&gt;$52 billion dollars in government aid&lt;/a&gt;. It was saving lives “right here, right now”. In comparison, developing effective ways to combat malaria gets relatively ignored, with a total worldwide funding of only about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.impatientoptimists.org/Posts/2013/12/World-Malaria-Report&quot; title=&quot;Impatient Optimists: World Makes Major Gains in Fight Against Malaria&quot;&gt;$2 billion a year&lt;/a&gt;. It’s saving lives in the future, of people who are far away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put things in perspective, Katrina killed almost two thousand people. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/health/healthnews/9058283/Malaria-death-toll-far-higher-than-previously-thought.html&quot; title=&quot;Telegraph: Malaria death toll far higher than previously thought&quot;&gt;Malaria kills 1.2 MILLION people each year&lt;/a&gt;. Both are tragedies, but malaria is a tragedy on such a scale that it boggles the mind. Even if it takes us 100 years to effectively fight Malaria, that’s suffering which is now eliminated for the &lt;em&gt;rest of human history&lt;/em&gt;. The long term counts. It counts a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not suggesting we ignore our current problems to only look at the future; one of the best ways of improving the future is by improving the present. But we shouldn’t be so quick to dismiss projects simply because they won’t come to fruition in our lifetimes. Nor should we dismiss a suggestion just because it “feels wrong”. In the past, organ transplants, pacemakers, and even &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ignaz_Semmelweis#Conflict_with_established_medical_opinions&quot; title=&quot;Ignaz Semmelweis - Conflict with established medical opinions&quot;&gt;washing your surgical instruments after performing an autopsy&lt;/a&gt; “felt wrong”. For many people today, the thought same-sex intercourse &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; “feels wrong”. The human brain is apt to &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; disgust and unease at things which are ethically very &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like more people to think how they can make the world—and the future—a better place. To do that, I need them to think about—and often question—their own beliefs. I delight when I find someone who supports their beliefs with evidence, and who accepts counter-evidence that may falsify their beliefs. These are people who are interested in the truth; and the truth is real whether you “believe” in it or not. These are the same people with whom discussing ethics is a delight, since they’re apt to establish a method of analysis that asks “what harm does this cause, and what benefits does it bring?” rather than to simply declare “it feels wrong” or “it feels right”. These are the people that most often have me question and change my own beliefs, and I love them dearly for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, our default wiring isn’t set that way, and it’s not hard to see why. If someone sacrifices their child to save the lives of a hundred others, that person is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; going to be universally praised; nor are they likely to even feel good about themselves. Yet if we put value on human lives, then clearly saving the lives of a hundred children is superior to saving just one, even if we feel deeply uncomfortable with the scenario posed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this brings me to my problem. I would like others to think about things rationally; in terms of harm and benefit, in terms of what overall good can be achieved in the world. I would like people to think about their ethical beliefs, and to question &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they feel that way, and whether that’s actually for the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, I would like for people to be more &lt;em&gt;aware&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That, in itself, is a hard problem. Ignorance is not only comforting, but it’s strengthening. If a person believes that same-sex marriage is wrong, or that we should turn refugees away from our borders, or that people with different coloured skin are inferior, then that person is unlikely to wish to consider evidence. A naive attempt to present them with evidence may even cause them to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reactance_(psychology)&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Reactance (psychology)&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;strengthen&lt;/em&gt; their beliefs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s a deeper problem for me personally, one that makes &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; feel uneasy. Living in a little bubble, being unaware of the injustices of the world, being unaware of how one contributes to those injustices… it’s &lt;em&gt;nice&lt;/em&gt;. Making people more &lt;em&gt;aware&lt;/em&gt; doesn’t make them more &lt;em&gt;happy&lt;/em&gt;; in fact it often does the reverse. Even if someone says they want to know the truth, even if they say they want to learn how to better question themselves and the world, learning the truth has potential to do personal harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s for this reason that I will leave someone’s religious beliefs alone, yet still argue passionately that condoms and sex education are a good idea. It’s for this reason I’ll accept the racist comments of a dying person with sympathy and support, yet pointedly question those same beliefs in a healthy individual. If someone has great power to enact change and make the world a better place—but insists on doing the reverse—then I will argue to the limits of what I consider ethical to try and change that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you find me questioning your beliefs—if you find me trying to change your mind—it means that I feel that you have both the intelligence to change, and the capacity to make the world a better place if you do so. If I’m trying to convince you that you’re wrong, then I’m most assuredly paying you a compliment. And if you’re able to change my own beliefs in the process, then I will be delighted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au///ethics/2013/12/15/the-ethics-of-everyday-people.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au///ethics/2013/12/15/the-ethics-of-everyday-people.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Obviously, they're a jerk</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;People are so completely incomprehensible sometimes. We look at the actions of others, and think “why would they do that?” and “what were they thinking?”. Often we explain their behaviour by ascribing them traits. Someone cuts you off and runs a red light? They’re obviously a jerk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we so often forgetting is that inside everyone’s head is a consistent story. They’re doing what they’re doing because it makes sense to them at the time. If the person who cut you off at the lights has someone bleeding out in the back-seat and is speeding to the hospital, then their actions seem heroic, not jerky. But to us, the outside observer, we come to the wrong conclusions for their actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we misattribute people’s behaviour all the time, even when those people are close to us. For me personally, October has been incredibly stressful. My father’s in hospital, I’ve spent weeks on divorce negotiations, I’ve been travelling far more than has been comfortable, there’s been tax, housemates moving out, housemates moving in, conference talks to write, work deadlines to meet, and my todo list is full to bursting. And that’s just the things I’m willing to talk about publicly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know for certain during this time that I’ve come across to some people as unreliable, uncaring, unresponsive, or unfriendly. That’s not been my intent, and I’ve tried to explain as best where I can, but sometimes explanations are not always possible. The best I can hope for is that others give me the benefit of the doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I have a request for you, and it has nothing to do with me. The next time you think that someone’s uncaring or rude, the next time you think someone’s unreliable or inconsistent; the next time you think someone must dislike you because they’re not responding to your communication; then please think for a moment. That person has an internal story where their behaviour makes sense. If their behaviour seems puzzling to you, it may well be because you don’t know that story. So please, give them the benefit of the doubt. They may not be as big a jerk as you think.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au///ethics/2013/10/29/obviously-theyre-a-jerk.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au///ethics/2013/10/29/obviously-theyre-a-jerk.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Remembering better times</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most frustrating thing about humans is that we’ll feel a particular way—happy, sad, angry, annoyed—and then we’ll find excuses as to &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; we’re feeling that way. If we’re feeling sad, it’s &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; hard to remember times when you were happy. If we’re feeling annoyed, then the most minor things can cause us to lose our cool, even if they’re things we’d hardly notice on better days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty clear that for whatever you’re feeling, that’s what you’ll be good at remembering. If you’re having a great time, you’ll be better at remembering similar happy memories. If you’re hitting a particular difficulty, it’s much too easy to remember all the other times you’ve hit the same difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we recognise our feelings are transient. When we’re feeling hungry, we know that’s a temporary state, even if it causes us to buy half the supermarket when we go shopping. But if we’re feeling sad or lonely, then it’s way too easy to think those are somehow permanent, because all the other similar occasions are what easily spring to mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the real struggles here is that there’s an actual block in being able to conjure up those other feelings. You might say, “I know I was feeling happy last Thursday”, but if you’re feeling rotten right now, then you’re just stuck with “knowing”, rather than “feeling”. That abstract knowledge might not make you feel any better—in fact unless you’ve actually sat down to honestly remember how you felt each day—you might not even remember that you were happy last Thursday in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, more than anything else, is why I track my moods. It’s why I journal my experiences. My memory is biased, and records and journals are one of the few ways of seeing how I actually felt at any given time. My challenge is to keep them up to date; if I’m having a great time—and sometimes if I’m having an awful time—then often they don’t get recorded, and I miss what are arguably some of my most important records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But even if you don’t track your moods and experiences, then at least remember that if you’re feeling down, or angry, or frustrated, then your brain—and your memory in particular—is going to actively mess with you. You may not be able to stop that from happening, but having knowledge and insight may at least help you make better choices than what you may have otherwise made.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au///depression/2013/10/29/feels-influence-perception.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au///depression/2013/10/29/feels-influence-perception.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>A hope for humanity</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s fascinating how some feelings can hit you entirely out of the blue, when you’d least expect them, but that’s what happened yesterday to me in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was exploring the local markets at Asasuka, and I’d found the Studio Ghibli store. There were all the things you’d expect: towels, handbags, keyrings, stickers, purses; nothing that I hadn’t really seen before, and certainly nothing that I thought would change how I feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except there was. In a display cabinet, at the back of the store, there was a model of one of the robots from &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Castle_in_the_Sky&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Laputa—Castle in the Sky&quot;&gt;Laputa: Castle in the Sky&lt;/a&gt;. A light layer of moss, bird’s nest on its shoulder, holding a flower. And, as a complete surprise to myself, I almost cried.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laputa has long been one of my favourite films. I probably watched it a dozen times while growing up. The imagery in it is striking, but the most moving part for me was its portrayal of technology. The robots that tend Laputa are kind and gentle; they are immortal caretakers and protectors of nature and humanity alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, when things start to go wrong, we discover the robots also have the capacity for destruction. That’s unfortunately true for technology in general; almost anything can be weaponised. But ultimately, technology allows us to make our lives better. We’ve never had such an amazing capacity to ease suffering, cure disease, travel distances, communicate, share, explore and discover as we have now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our understanding of modern science is still very much in its infancy. A hundred years ago we were only just getting started with electricity, and the results have been incredible. Right now, we’re still just getting started with microbiology and genetics. I think we have a future where we don’t just cure cancer, but a future where we &lt;em&gt;eliminate disease&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways, the robotic caretakers of Laputa symbolise my hopes for humanity. Technology is already our caretaker; modern cities simply couldn’t exist without automation, and for someone with a pacemaker or insulin pump, technology is a central part of simply being alive. I know that we’re going to get things wrong along the way—technology is already used for warfare and oppression—but it’s my most sincere hope that our relationship with technology will allow us to become more compassionate, more creative, more inquisitive, and more &lt;em&gt;human&lt;/em&gt; than we’ve ever been before. There is a nurturing and caring future for humanity, we just need to reach it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very rare for me to ever purchase something as a memento of my travels, but yesterday I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au///ethics/2013/09/30/a-hope-for-humanity.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au///ethics/2013/09/30/a-hope-for-humanity.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Fear, Uncertainty, and Dopamine</title>
				<description>&lt;div class='video-container'&gt;&lt;iframe height='420' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/e0H0BKrF4HY?html5=1' width='560'&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e0H0BKrF4HY'&gt;Watch on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A discussion of community building from a psychological perspective. How to recruit people into your project, external and internal motivations, what people regret, self-fulfilling prophecies, confirmation bias, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au///talks/2013/07/26/fear-uncertainty-and-dopamine.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au///talks/2013/07/26/fear-uncertainty-and-dopamine.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Depression: Bugs In Your Brain</title>
				<description>&lt;div class='video-container'&gt;&lt;iframe height='420' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/H8e4rQZPmQ?html5=1' width='560'&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H8e4rQZPmQ'&gt;Watch on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I gave a presentation at OSCON on both my experiences with and the science of depression. The video of that presentation is above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a video of hope. It’s not a video of “everything is going to be okay”, because there’s no way I can say that. It’s a video discussing what it’s like, and some of the research as to what’s going on in your brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a video that says that you are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depression is terrible. It makes it hard to look forward to anything. Decisions are difficult, because none of them seem worthwhile. It can make you lonely, and at the same time make the thought of seeing other people unpalatable. It can make you frustrated, but nothing seems to relieve that frustration, nothing seems to have meaning any more. And it can continue, all by itself. Once it starts, you can be depressed &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; you’re depressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depression has taken some of the best and brightest people in Open Source. I’m deeply grateful that the OSCON chairs agreed—on short notice—for me to have a location and film crew for this talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been sitting on the video for a while. I’ve been meaning to watch it—but for my own personal reasons—I haven’t been able to do so. If you’re the sort who &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; want the science, skip forward to minute 12. If you only want my personal experiences, you can stop watching at the same point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much for your time, and especially thank you to everyone who has been so supportive and caring when I’ve struggled. Please don’t hesitate to share this talk widely. If you wish for me to speak on depression at your conference or event—and can find a way for me to get there—I’ll be happy to oblige.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au///talks/2013/07/24/depression-bugs-in-your-brain.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au///talks/2013/07/24/depression-bugs-in-your-brain.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                     
	</channel>
</rss>
