<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>paul.j.fenwick</title>
		<description>Freedom Loving Scientist</description>
		<link>http://pjf.id.au</link>
		<atom:link href="http://pjf.id.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Just Love Each Other</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen an &lt;a href=&quot;http://polyamorydiaries.com/im-madly-in-love-with-you-but-dont-worry-its-not-a-big-deal/&quot; title=&quot;I'm madly in love with you, but don't worry, it's not a big deal&quot;&gt;article on love doing the rounds&lt;/a&gt; recently, and I’m really glad to see this. People fall in love all the time, but society keeps telling us there’s only one type of love that counts, and we have an unhealthy societal expectation that we shouldn’t tell people that we love them unless they are “the one”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even without having studied relational psychology, it’s not hard to see that we’re using one word for many different things. Sternberg¹ splits love into three components: “Intimacy” (closeness, connectedness), “Passion” (physical attraction, sex), and “Dedication” (cognition, planning, commitment). A lot of long-term relationships end up having intimacy and dedication, and we call that love. A lot of friendships have the same, but many people hesitate to say “I love you” to their friends. And heaven forbid that you say “I love you” to someone you’re actually having passionate relations with, in case they’re not &lt;em&gt;the one&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as importantly, we’re seen a new wave of discussions that recognise that there are many types of attraction other than just sexual attraction. The Asexual Visibility and Education Network wiki lists at least &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asexuality.org/wiki/index.php?title=Attraction&quot; title=&quot;AVEN Wiki on attraction&quot;&gt;four types of attraction&lt;/a&gt;: sexual, romantic, sensual, and aesthetic. Attraction is not a single axis-scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Society teaches so many things about relationships which aren’t healthy. It denies that people feel different kinds of love, different kinds of attraction, and may feel these towards many people at once. We broadly define things as being “right” or “wrong” based upon expectations that relationships should fall into well defined categories: partner, friend, colleague, family member. These well-defined relationships come with well-defined behaviours that are acceptable and unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is bollocks. So much friggin’ bollocks. As a society we’re stopping people from telling their friends that they’re loved. We have expectations that if someone is in love they &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; want to have sex. We struggle with people having multiple romantic or sexual relationships, and when we do accept people with multiple relations we &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; seem obsessed into classifying those into boxes. And don’t even get me started on sexuality, slut shaming, kink, and gender roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sick of this. Not all humans, and not all human relationships fall into neat boxes. They’re dynamic, complex, messy, and &lt;em&gt;fucking beautiful&lt;/em&gt;, and society be damned if your relationships don’t fall into the scripts you’ve been taught from childhood. Don’t let someone else tell you that your relationships have to be monogamous or non-monogamous, sexual or asexual, romantic or aromantic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, do all the things I struggle to do. They’re hard, I know, because I’m worried I might be taken the wrong way, because I’m terrified that I’ll be stigmatised, because I’ve been taught that relationships &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; fall into neat categories. Talk to each other. Talk about the relationships you have. Talk about the relationships you’d &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; to have. Tell your friends that you love them. Encourage healthy relationships, &lt;em&gt;no matter what their form&lt;/em&gt;, no matter how suitable or unsuitable you feel they’d be for you personally. Enter relationships not with the expectations of society or the sub-culture in which you’ve been most influenced, but with the expectation that you’ll communicate about how you feel, and you’ll do that with honesty and respect. Follow a relationship path not because it’s what’s expected of you, but instead because it’s something you passionately want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¹ Sternberg, R.J. “A Triangular Theory of Love.” Psychological Review 93, no. 2 (1986): 119.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cover image &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.torange.us/Holidays/valentines-day/Inscription-I-love-you-17591.html&quot;&gt;CC-BY-4.0 T-Orange&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2015/12/25/just-love-each-other.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2015/12/25/just-love-each-other.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Duck Yes! SpaceX lands their Falcon 9!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;DUCK YES! SpaceX landed their first Falcon 9 today after it successfully deployed its payload to orbit. This is big news, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/AndyWeirAuthor/photos/a.463868883712409.1073741828.462962073803090/834802823285678/&quot;&gt;to quote Andy Weir&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Imagine if you took a flight from New York to London. And then, when you were done, they threw the plane away. Want to go back? Well, they’ll have to make a new plane. Imagine what air travel tickets would cost if the airline industry worked that way. Well, that’s exactly how the space industry works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Or at least, that’s how it &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; to work. Until today. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy’s pretty good at explanations, but at this point at least one of you would be thinking “but what about the Space Shuttle? That was reusable!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you’re right, the orbiter was reusable, that was its primary role. The boosters were reusable, they were dropped in the atmosphere and had parachutes, but they’d land in the ocean and require a bunch of cleaning up first. The external tank was not reusable, it was jettisoned in space and would break up in the atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Space Shuttle was also breathtakingly expensive. It cost $450 million to $1.5 billion dollars &lt;em&gt;per launch&lt;/em&gt;. The system from SpaceX, the Falcon 9, costs a mere $61.2 million per launch, and it has a comparable payload to the Space Shuttle.. In terms of putting things into space, it’s cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s why a successful Falcon 9 landing is such a huge step-forward. It’s a system that can return itself from orbit and land on a pad &lt;em&gt;by itself&lt;/em&gt;. Rather than having to build a new rocket &lt;em&gt;every time&lt;/em&gt;, or clean and test something that’s landed in the ocean (salt-water is not good for spacecraft), you instead have something you can test, service, and re-use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that it’s just the first (lower) stage which is able to self-land at the moment. The second stage (which delivers the payload) isn’t re-usable yet, but that’s the next step, and I’m quite certain we’ll see it self-landing before long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having both stages be able to land themselves means we’d see that $61.2m launch cost drop to an estimated $5–7m, which is pretty friggin’ amazing. It could be even less; the cost of fuel is only 0.3% of the vehicle costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really can’t express how amazed I am by this. We’d be looking at being able to do HUNDREDS of launches for the same price as a single Space Shuttle launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bravo, SpaceX, you rock!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/1B6oiLNyKKI?html5=1&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1B6oiLNyKKI&quot;&gt;Watch on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/12/22/spacex-lands-rocket-duck-yes.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/12/22/spacex-lands-rocket-duck-yes.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>BuzzConf Was Awesome</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve just come back from &lt;a href=&quot;https://buzzconf.io/&quot;&gt;BuzzConf&lt;/a&gt;, and I’m so excited by it that I’ve started writing about it even before my first coffee in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a unique blend of conference and festival, BuzzConf was good. &lt;em&gt;Really&lt;/em&gt; good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;atmosphere&quot;&gt;Atmosphere&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Great location for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/buzzconf?src=hash&quot;&gt;#buzzconf&lt;/a&gt; at Pheonix Park, Ballan and awesome talk line up &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/GpGiFNxaeo&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/GpGiFNxaeo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; alexjmackey (@alexjmackey) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/alexjmackey/status/665312803054448640&quot;&gt;November 13, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://phoenixparkballan.com.au/&quot;&gt;Phoenix Park&lt;/a&gt; campgrounds, BuzzConf had a sunny and cheerful location that wasn’t too far out of Melbourne, and with pretty darn great facilities. A number of big tents had been erected to act as lecture theatres, as well as providing space for the hackathon. There was a well-equipped stage for musicians and announcements. My tent had both WiFi and power, and there were on-site dorms for those who didn’t wish to camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The environment of BuzzConf was a huge factor in making it a success. There was lots of natural light. There was a common outdoor area that was perfect for meeting, dancing, warming oneself by the fire, eating, and everything else. It was easy to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; worry about day-to-day things and be in the moment, and because everyone was staying on-site there was a much greater feel of community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;talks&quot;&gt;Talks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;So excited to hear &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KathyReid&quot;&gt;@KathyReid&lt;/a&gt; talk about the convergence of computing &amp;amp; biomedical industry &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/BuzzConf?src=hash&quot;&gt;#BuzzConf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/ylWsOdXoq8&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/ylWsOdXoq8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ruth Ellison (@RuthEllison) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RuthEllison/status/665667186883596288&quot;&gt;November 14, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scheduled talks were also nothing short of amazing. I was honoured to give an opening on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0op6Wucdv7E&quot;&gt;future and emerging technologies&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjf/future-is-awesome&quot;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;), and we had outstanding talks by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kathyreid&quot; class=&quot;social-link&quot;&gt;@kathyreid&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://buzzconf.io/sessions/the-human-body-as-a-development-platform/&quot;&gt;the human body as a development platform&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/KathyReid/buzzconf-2015-presentation&quot;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/auastro&quot; class=&quot;social-link&quot;&gt;@auastro&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://andy.kitchen/buzz-conf/&quot;&gt;machine learning&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ErikHallander&quot; class=&quot;social-link&quot;&gt;@ErikHallander&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://buzzconf.io/sessions/disruption_that_has_genuine_impact/&quot;&gt;disruptive technologies in medicine&lt;/a&gt;. I have been to &lt;a href=&quot;http://lanyrd.com/profile/pjf/past/&quot;&gt;a lot&lt;/a&gt; of conferences, and I can say hands down that the talks at BuzzConf were &lt;em&gt;outstanding&lt;/em&gt;. In particular, the talks &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; succeeded in setting a theme. Everywhere I went, people were talking about the future, and—most pleasing for me—&lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; of these conversations had a core theme of what’s the best we can achieve for humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;entertainment&quot;&gt;Entertainment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;fancybox&quot; rel=&quot;group&quot; href=&quot;/images/tech/BFR.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tech/BFR.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Big Fucking Robots seriously win at stage presence.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evenings we had &lt;a href=&quot;https://buzzconf.io/the-music/&quot;&gt;live music&lt;/a&gt;, starting with blues and roots with the likes of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lisaspykers.com/&quot;&gt;Lisa Spykers&lt;/a&gt;, and ending with the amazing high-energy &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/bigfuckingrobots/&quot;&gt;Big Fucking Robots&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; got people dancing. I’ve seen lots of tech conferences &lt;em&gt;try&lt;/em&gt; to get people to dance, but BuzzConf and BFR actually pulled it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;family&quot;&gt;Family&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I have a new toy via nodebot workshop at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/buzzconf?src=hash&quot;&gt;#buzzconf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Mmnw4HMCTQ&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Mmnw4HMCTQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Stephen Edmonds (@popcorncx) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/popcorncx/status/665371058090852352&quot;&gt;November 14, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BuzzConf was an intentionally kids-friendly event, with lots of maker-focused activities for both kids and adults alike, and free attendence for children aged sixteen or under. This is something I’m &lt;em&gt;hugely&lt;/em&gt; supportive of, as it’s a big step up for inclusiveness and diversity, and all the kids I saw seemed to be having the &lt;em&gt;best time ever&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I hope you get the idea that &lt;em&gt;BuzzConf was incredible&lt;/em&gt;, which is why I am delighted that it will be happening again next year, and why I’d like to share some of my own thoughts on how to make it &lt;em&gt;even better&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;food&quot;&gt;Food&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found the food situation at BuzzConf to be jarring. Rather than being included in the ticket price, food was an additional cost for participants. This would be cool if everyone was strongly encouraged to bring their own, but instead I felt we were encouraged to bring money, leaving most people with little option but to buy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Captive_market&quot;&gt;captively priced&lt;/a&gt; food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though it may be the same cost to participants, I feel that raising the ticket price and having BuzzConf be a fully catered event would have been a much better solution, not just in terms of participants feeling they were getting a good deal, but also a more fair solution for participants on low-income concession tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By all means, charge extra for alcohol and fancy coffee, but unless participants are strongly reminded and encouragred to bring their own food, captively priced food feels wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hackathon&quot;&gt;Hackathon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Dear &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/Buzzconf?src=hash&quot;&gt;#Buzzconf&lt;/a&gt; hackathon participants, I know there&amp;#39;s a judging round, but this is how I feel about you all. &amp;lt;3 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/dE8nLtQNsf&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/dE8nLtQNsf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Paul Fenwick (@pjf) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pjf/status/665755789378760704&quot;&gt;November 15, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of things I don’t like about where hackathons are headed. Rather than being oriented around the joy of creation, or making the world a better place, it feels that the modern hackathon is oriented around competition, themes which overtly advantage the sponsors, judging, and cash prizes. These are themes that don’t encourage collaboration and open sharing, which I feel should be a core theme of not just BuzzConf, but of humanity’s future in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I usually don’t participate in these sorts of hackathons, and was &lt;em&gt;very surprised&lt;/em&gt; when I was asked to judge the &lt;a href=&quot;https://buzzconf.io/hackathon/sharing-economy/&quot;&gt;BuzzConf hackathon&lt;/a&gt;; especially when I was asked to rate projects on a short timeframe against criteria such as “most futuristic” or “most benefit to the sharing economy”, and which was lacking on criteria like “most good for humanity”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that having a hacking space at conferences is a &lt;em&gt;fantastic&lt;/em&gt; idea, but I am much, much more in favour of having a free creative space like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://opensourcebridge.org/blog/2011/03/hacker-lounge-returns-to-open-source-bridge/&quot;&gt;Open Source Bridge hacker lounge&lt;/a&gt;, or an intentionally fun and collaborative &lt;a href=&quot;http://takeitbackathon.com/&quot;&gt;Take It Back-athon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unconference&quot;&gt;Unconference&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I friggin’ &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unconference&quot;&gt;unconferences&lt;/a&gt;, and so was delighted with the expectation that BuzzConf would be “a conference in the morning, an unconference in the afternoon, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burning_Man&quot;&gt;burn&lt;/a&gt; in the evening”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the BuzzConf unconference component didn’t feel like it worked. It was scheduled in a small space, which didn’t have projectors or A/V equipment, and which was in competition with other activities. I didn’t turn up to the unconference component on the second day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unconferences are great because they result in lots of participation, but for that to work they need lots of participants, appropriate facilities for presentation and discussion, and a basic skeleton of timeslots to get people started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d be very much in favour of dropping the unconference section of BuzzConf if it’s going to be in competition with other activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;future-thoughts&quot;&gt;Future Thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many things I think would work well at BuzzConf, and almost all of them are oriented around participation. A dedicated (uncontested) slot for lightning talks would be amazing. Encouraging many of the best aspects of Burning Man culture like sharing, theme camps, art, and costumes. Giant writing spaces for people to leave notes and thoughts, decorate, and use as they think best. Extending free or discounted tickets (even if just day passes) to the residents of Ballan, so the local community is able to experience and participate in the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But one thing is for sure, I’m very, &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; impressed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://buzzconf.io&quot;&gt;BuzzConf 2015&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ll be sure to come back next year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you liked this article, or my talks at BuzzConf and other conferences, consider supporting me &lt;a href=&quot;https://patreon.com/_pjf&quot;&gt;on patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/11/16/buzzconf-was-awesome.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/11/16/buzzconf-was-awesome.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>It's time we spoke about loneliness</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Okay folks, it’s time to talk about mental health again. Today we’re going to be discussing one of the most common and yet stigma-laden topics of all: loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of people feel lonely. An estimated 20% of the United States population experiences loneliness, and amongst groups prone to social isolation that can be much, much higher. Loneliness isn’t just unpleasant, either; it’s associated with a mortality risk about equal to that of smoking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if there’s one thing we don’t like to admit, it’s that we’re lonely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loneliness comes with a whole barrel of stigmas associated with it. Saying that you’re lonely can make you feel like a failure, and comes with the real concern that others will feel the same. Loneliness can make you less effective at everything, which means it’s easy to find evidence for your fears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s more, loneliness can have nothing to do with popularity, or number of friends. You can have an active social life and still be lonely. When Stephen Fry battled with depression, he said that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stephenfry.com/2013/06/24/only-the-lonely/&quot;&gt;loneliness was the worst part&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Lonely? I get invitation cards through the post almost every day. I shall be in the Royal Box at Wimbledon and I have serious and generous offers from friends asking me to join them in the South of France, Italy, Sicily, South Africa, British Columbia, and America this summer. I have two months to start a book before I go off to Broadway for a run of Twelfth Night there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I can read back that last sentence and see that, bipolar or not, if I’m under treatment and not actually depressed, what the fuck right do I have to be lonely, unhappy, or forlorn? I don’t have the right. But there again I don’t have the right not to have those feelings. Feelings are not something to which one does or does not have rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the end loneliness is the most terrible and contradictory of my problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradoxically, loneliness can &lt;em&gt;increase&lt;/em&gt; social aversion; highly social people will wall themselves up and hide from the world when they’re lonely. Many studies have found that loneliness increases the aversion to close human contact, even when we know that’s what we need. It’s easy to feel one can be a drag, or won’t fit in, or worst of all rejection: that your fear that nobody wants to spend time with you is actually real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s been a lot of studies between social media and loneliness. We know there’s a correlation between loneliness and social media, but we don’t know if there’s causality; it would make sense for lonely people to spend more time in a social medium, even if it can be questioned if that medium provides the sort of close interpersonal interactions that can make a difference to loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because this is something with so much stigma associated with it, because this is something that we hate to admit to ourselves (let alone others), I’m going to say this straight: I’m lonely. Not always, not all the time, but often enough. It gets in the way of my work. It turns me into a recluse. It certainly gets in the way of me being the person that I want to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if this comes as a surprise, then I’ve done my hiding well. When I’m socialising with others, I’m usually &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; lonely. If I’m talking about how I’ve been, then loneliness is the &lt;em&gt;last&lt;/em&gt; thing I want to mention, because saying that genuinely makes me feel that I’ve failed. But the moment other people are gone, then more often than not the feeling of loneliness returns, and I’ll hide away from the world as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a cry for help, nor a request for assistance. It is a refusal to remain quiet despite the stigmas we have when discussing mental health. It’s me saying “hey, it’s not just you”, for as much good as that will do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to offer advice, I don’t even think my advice may be worth that much, but I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; tell you that loneliness is extremely common as well as extremely hidden. No matter what you may think, you are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selected references (if you read any, read the first):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Olien, Jessica. “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/articles/health_and_science/medical_examiner/2013/08/dangers_of_loneliness_social_isolation_is_deadlier_than_obesity.html&quot;&gt;Loneliness Is Deadly.&lt;/a&gt;” Slate, August 23, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boomsma, D. I., G. Willemsen, C. V. Dolan, L. C. Hawkley, and J. T. Cacioppo. “Genetic and Environmental Contributions to Loneliness in Adults: The Netherlands Twin Register Study.” Behavior Genetics 35, no. 6 (2005): 745–52.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cacioppo, John T., and Stephanie Cacioppo. “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4021390/&quot;&gt;Social Relationships and Health: The Toxic Effects of Perceived Social Isolation.&lt;/a&gt;” Social and Personality Psychology Compass 8, no. 2 (February 1, 2014): 58–72. doi:10.1111/spc3.12087.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fry, Stephen. “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stephenfry.com/2013/06/24/only-the-lonely/&quot;&gt;Only The Lonely.&lt;/a&gt;” Official Site of Stephen Fry. Accessed September 6, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawkley, Louise C., and John T. Cacioppo. “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3874845/&quot;&gt;Loneliness Matters: A Theoretical and Empirical Review of Consequences and Mechanisms.&lt;/a&gt;” Annals of Behavioral Medicine : A Publication of the Society of Behavioral Medicine 40, no. 2 (October 2010). doi:10.1007/s12160-010-9210-8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holt-Lunstad, Julianne, Timothy B. Smith, and J. Bradley Layton. “Social Relationships and Mortality Risk: A Meta-Analytic Review.” PLoS Med 7, no. 7 (July 27, 2010): e1000316. doi:10.1371/journal.pmed.1000316.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilson, C., and B. Moulton. “Loneliness among Older Adults: A National Survey of Adults 45+.” Prepared by Knowledge Networks and Insight Policy Research. Washington, DC: AAR, 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/depression/2015/09/06/its-time-we-spoke-about-loneliness.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/depression/2015/09/06/its-time-we-spoke-about-loneliness.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>I've pledged to give 10% of my income to causes that do the most good</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, 16th August I made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.givingwhatwecan.org/pledge&quot; title=&quot;Giving What We Can Pledge&quot;&gt;pledge&lt;/a&gt;. A lifelong pledge to give 10% of my income to causes that do the most good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I should have done a long time ago, and for years I had found excuses not to do so. I was saving for a house. I was building financial security. It wasn’t &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; fault that injustice and hardship existed elsewhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it is. It’s totally my fault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The food I eat is transported and grown with petroleum products which &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hrw.org/africa/equatorial-guinea&quot;&gt;support corrupt regimes&lt;/a&gt; that keep people in poverty. The electricity that powers my laptop, the trains that I catch, and the public lighting I enjoy, comes from environmental destruction and greenhouse gas emission. The animal products I use are the result of cruelty and suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal choices can lessen the negative impact I make on the world, but no amount of being car-free or using green energy will eliminate the damage I’m causing. But there is something I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do. I can take responsibility. I can try to make amends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I live in one of the richest countries on Earth. I have financial, health, housing, and food security. I have valuable and transferrable skills. I’ve had &lt;a href=&quot;http://thewireless.co.nz/articles/the-pencilsword-on-a-plate&quot;&gt;opportunities&lt;/a&gt; that much of the world’s population—even those here in Australia—simply never had. At a relatively small cost to me I can make a large difference elsewhere, and I feel it is my moral obligation to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most effective charities in the world are &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; effective. 200 &lt;em&gt;million&lt;/em&gt; people suffer from malaria each year, and of those, up to 800,000 will die. In the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC), 500 people die &lt;em&gt;per day&lt;/em&gt;, the vast majority of which are children under five.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you know what stops malaria? Bed-nets. Treated with insecticide, these not only protect the people they’re distributed to, but they kill the mosquitoes that spread disease, protecting the entire community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost of distributing a net in the DRC—one of the most difficult places in the world to work—is about $7.50 USD, inclusive of all expenses, which include follow-up studies to ensure correct deployment and use. For every thousand children protected with nets, 5.5 lives are saved¹.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cost-per-life-saved is a little higher than one may get from naive calculations; not every net is used effectively, nets need to be replaced over time, and there are other factors at play. &lt;a href=&quot;http://givewell.org/&quot;&gt;GiveWell&lt;/a&gt; estimates a cost of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.givewell.org/international/top-charities/AMF#Costperlifesaved&quot;&gt;just under $3,500 USD per life saved&lt;/a&gt;. Through lifelong giving I have the opportunity to impact &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; lives, and to do genuine good in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure I remain committed to this pledge, Thomas Hendrey has pledged with me, and we’ll be checking each other’s progress each year. But I would also like &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; to join me in doing good. Even if you &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.givingwhatwecan.org/try-giving&quot;&gt;pledge just 1%&lt;/a&gt; of your income for a year, that’s a real diffence that can be made. I’ve chosen to do this in conjunction with &lt;a href=&quot;https://givingwhatwecan.org/&quot;&gt;Giving What We Can&lt;/a&gt;, as they provide tracking and support for pledgers, but I am also personally willing to provide social support in helping you keep that pledge. One of my biggest psychological barriers was finding other people to join me in doing good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¹ Lengeler, Christian. “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bibliotecacochrane.com/pdf/CD000363.pdf&quot;&gt;Insecticide-Treated Bed Nets and Curtains for Preventing Malaria.&lt;/a&gt;” In Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, edited by The Cochrane Collaboration. Chichester, UK: John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons, Ltd, 2004.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/ethics/2015/08/20/im-donating-10pc-of-my-income-to-charity.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/ethics/2015/08/20/im-donating-10pc-of-my-income-to-charity.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Human relevance in the age of machines</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The industrial revolution’s defining feature was the mass-production of machines that could do jobs &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; than human workers. This was a change so profound that British Parliament passed a law in 1812 making &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Destruction_of_Stocking_Frames,_etc._Act_1812&quot;&gt;destruction of a robot worker a &lt;em&gt;capital offence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. While that law no longer exists, there still exists an ongoing and relevant concern that humans will be replaced with machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the focus is on machines replacing human labour, resulting in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technological_unemployment&quot;&gt;technological unemployment&lt;/a&gt;; but I’m concerned about something much more frightening: what if machines can do &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; better than humans? What if they’re not only better workers, but better authors, better artists, better chefs, and better lovers? What happens when the machines can offer us anything we want… &lt;a href=&quot;http://dresdencodak.com/2008/06/07/eloi/&quot;&gt;save relevance&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relevance is a fascinating term, and as a species we have &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; struggled it. Religion, work, family, conflict, exploration, hardship, art, justice, discovery… all these things have given us relevance throughout the generations, and what gives our own lives relevance varies from person to person. The idea that employment gives our life relevance is certainly advantageous for a capitalist society, but it’s also clear that for many people employment makes them feel &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; relevant: it takes them away from the things they truly love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, relevance is supplied purely by “artificial” factors; I’ve seen people go to great lengths working on their characters in massively multiplayer games, and it’s very clear these people find relevance in doing so. I’ve met people who find relevance in knowing the contents of a book or movie extremely well, even though they are the audience and not the creator. I persist in dabbling in calligraphy and writing, even though it’s abundantly clear that I’m not the best at these, nor will ever be the best. I don’t expect these to have relevance beyond the smallest of groups, and yet that act of creation gives my own life relevance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to the humanity of the future gives me a newfound appreciation of &lt;em&gt;art&lt;/em&gt;, for art may be undertaken for art’s sake alone. Few people build a megastructure in Minecraft expecting to make money from it, but it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; art and it provides purpose nonetheless. Few teenagers write terrible poetry truly expecting it to change the world, or even with the expectation of showing it to others; but—if my own history is anything to go by—teenagers will continue write terrible poetry, and it will be relevant to &lt;em&gt;themeselves&lt;/em&gt; nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The joy of creation is a joy that exists even though other people can do the same thing better, even though one’s skills may still be fledgling, and even if that creation doesn’t change the world in ways society tells us are important. The act of creation as a gift remains a highly relevant social act; the cake you baked &lt;em&gt;yourself&lt;/em&gt; means more to your loved ones than the cake you purchased, even though the purchased cake is “better” in all other ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a future where machines are better at everything, I feel that humans will &lt;em&gt;continue&lt;/em&gt; to have relevance, for no other reason than because as a species we have &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; found ways to feel relevant in the face of ever-changing circumstances. Humans feel joy from learning, even when their discoveries are not new. Humans feel important in their social circles, even when their social circles are in no way extraordinary. Humans will continue to create and work towards goals, even when others have already achieved them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not to say that all humans will feel relevant in this future, but not all humans feel relevant &lt;em&gt;today&lt;/em&gt;. In a world where machines are better at everything, they may be also be better &lt;em&gt;guides&lt;/em&gt;, helping humans to find a feeling of purpose and relevance in an otherwise uncaring universe; potentially transforming an uncaring universe into a caring one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s my big concern for the future; are the machines &lt;em&gt;we&lt;/em&gt; create placed in a role that cares for humanity, or is indifferent to it? When it comes down to tough decisions, does your machine doctor seek to find diseases early so they can be treated early, or so your insurance agency can hike your premiums? Does your personal agent exist to ease the burdens of your day, or to maximise advertising revenue? Does your automated car seek to minimise accidents and harm, or does it seek to minimise legal exposure of its manufacturer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All those questions are relevant today, as all those technologies are &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; today, but the current answers are not ones that I feel comfortable with, and not ones which are best for the future of humanity. I am convinced more and more that we should not be afraid of the machines of the future, but the &lt;em&gt;systems&lt;/em&gt; which cause those machines to come into existence; for as long as we develop technology for profit and not the greater good, there will be a misalignment between the trajectory we are presently on, and the future that would provide humanity and its creations greater relevance than ever before. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/08/04/how-will-humans-remain-relevant.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/08/04/how-will-humans-remain-relevant.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Noirin</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I met Noirin at OSCON, many years ago. Actually, I think it was the community leadership summit before OSCON. I was being me—meeting everyone—and one of those people was Noirin. I don’t remember the conversation exactly, but they must have asked me what I was working on, because I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; remember giving them a presentation of my Ignite talk (which I was nervous about) and asking for feedback (which they very generously gave). That started a long tradition of Noirin giving me feedback on my talks; ones that I had done, ones that I was working on, ones that were just thoughts in my head. And as part of that process and the friendship that surrounded it, I discovered something wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way in which Noirin saw the world was beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noirin would send me letters about their day. Some of them would be the most trivial things, like a bus trip home from work, but they were described with such wonder and enthusiasm and joy that they were an absolute delight to read. They would describe the crunch of the leaves beneath their boots, the way in which the wind caught their hair, and the sun shining through the leaves of a tree. Letters from Noirin were magical, and I cherished them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noirin was always delighted with adventures. I remember exploring the tunnels under Melbourne and doing light-painting with them. I remember handing them a non-venomous jellyfish on a beach in Australia. I remember us being dressed as pirates, at a rooftop bar in Portland, and Noirin handing me a shot-glass of “chilli-infused midori” and watching—with a twinkle in their eye and a huge grin on their face—as I consumed a shot of &lt;em&gt;habanero lube&lt;/em&gt;. It remains the best prank anyone has ever played on me, and I appreciated it both now and back then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noirin was understanding and supportive in times when &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; had it hard. I remember when I was sad and worn out and not really sure what I was doing with my life, and Noirin would just check on me, no matter where I was in the world, to see how I was doing, to tell me jokes and stories, and to make sure I was feeling better as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember Noirin insisting I eat an enormous amount of food at thanksgiving. I remember Noirin insisting that I should have their camera, because I had recently discovered the joys of photography. I remember Noirin telling me that everyone in Ireland knew each other, and then meeting Diane while dressed as Santa on the other side of the world, and discovering Noirin’s insistence to be true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember having a really, really bad day, and Noirin telling me they had organised an Amanda Palmer concert, and that I should MC it because no matter how much &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; didn’t believe in myself at the time, &lt;em&gt;Noirin&lt;/em&gt; believed in me. It was one of the best days of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Noirin, for the memories, for the support, for the love, and for all the joy and wonder you brought not just into my life, but into the lives of those around you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love you, Noirin, rest in peace. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2015/07/29/noirin.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2015/07/29/noirin.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>The Past and Future CKAN</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been almost five months since the first version of the Comprehensive
Kerbal Archive Network (CKAN) was released. What started as a desire to
make it easier to install and manage Kerbal mods has now turned into a
system that’s used by tens of thousands of users, along with hundreds
of contributors to our metadata and code. The CKAN has been a &lt;em&gt;huge&lt;/em&gt;
success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month, I posted saying that we were 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/03/12/ckan-infrastructure-sponsor-needed.html&quot;&gt;looking for an infrastructure sponsor&lt;/a&gt;
to help us with our growing needs, and I’m delighted to say that
search has been successful. We’re very grateful to 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/&quot;&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/a&gt; for their ongoing support.
With the help of AWS, we’re not only ensuring that mods are indexed
quickly and our code is continuously tested, but we’re also mirroring
thousands of past and present mod releases. We’re looking forward to
future CKAN clients being faster and more reliable than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our biggest challenges at the moment are not technical, but instead
time pressures faced by many of our key contributors. All the CKAN
developers work on the project in their spare time, and we have some
outstandingly talented people. However that means they’re
also starting companies, running successful businesses, jumping out
of airplanes, or having rich and varied lives that compete for their
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to ensure the continued development and support of the CKAN,
I’d like to move it out of the things I do when I have spare time,
and instead into the things I do as part of my job, with regular code
sprints, scheduled work days, progress reports, and accountability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I run my own software consultancy, so having the CKAN as part of my
job is entirely possible, but it means turning down other projects to
make time for it. To see if this is possible, I’ve created a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://patreon.com/pjf0&quot;&gt;patreon page&lt;/a&gt; to support my CKAN
development efforts. I’ve already got co-working space and a huge
amount of coffee booked for the 12th April, so if we hit our first
funding milestone by that time, it will be the first CKAN sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of whether we make the funding goals or not, I still intend
to work on the CKAN during my spare time as I always have. However if
successful I’m looking forward to being able to devote more and
regular hours to CKAN development and support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For everyone who has contributed to the project, &lt;em&gt;thank you&lt;/em&gt; for
helping make it the incredible success that it is today. It’s been
a pleasure working with you, and I look forward to doing even more of
the same in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to support me in developing the CKAN, or simply learn
more about my plans, please visit my
&lt;a href=&quot;https://patreon.com/pjf0&quot;&gt;patreon page&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul
(CKAN project founder)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/04/05/the-past-and-future-ckan.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/04/05/the-past-and-future-ckan.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>CKAN needs an infrastructure sponsor!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;About six months ago I had this crazy idea that one of my favourite games, Kerbal Space Program, needed a mod manager that did everything &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;, and an &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt; team of volunteers, including myself, set about to make that happen. The result has been the Comprehensive Kerbal Archive Network (CKAN). Tens of thousands of people have downloaded the CKAN client, and we index hundreds of mods to make sure our users can install and upgrade mods with the click of a button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CKAN has been an &lt;em&gt;overwhelming&lt;/em&gt; success. All our code is free, all our metadata is free, and all the work has been done by unpaid volunteers who wanted to contribute to something awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the CKAN requires infrastructure to run… and that’s not free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the services provided by the CKAN is the hosting of dedicated mirrors. These protect our users from outages, and ensure that mods which allow redistribution don’t suddenly cease-to-be if the site hosting them disappears. In December, each mirror required about 5GB of space. Now, due to our continued success, it’s about 20GB. However that’s only mirroring the latest version of each mod; we’d &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; to mirror older versions as well, for players running on older versions of KSP, or players who need to backgrade because they’ve encountered a bug in a new mod release. We also have much more modest requirements for our build and continuous-integration server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, those infrastructure costs are being borne by the same volunteers who contribute to the CKAN, in particular Alexander Dzhoganov (aka nlight) who has been managing the infrastructure, as well as being project lead for much of 2015. Alexander is an &lt;em&gt;absolute hero&lt;/em&gt; for doing this, but the growing popularity of the project is rapidly making this unsustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so this is where you &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; come in. If you happen to work for a company that can provision us an instance with some 400GB of storage on a fast pipe, the potential for a few hundred gigabytes of traffic each month, and the willingness to grow with our needs, then we’ll think you’re &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;, and you’ll have saved the CKAN mirror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our first mirror and most important mirror we need an instance we can configure and run ourselves. We have bots that index all the mods, test everything installs, watches the git repo for changes, and provide amazing continuous integration tests. That instance is our main automation workhorse, it simply can’t work unless we can control it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the first mirror is re-homed, we can establish more traditional mirrors, and I’m thankful for everyone who’s offered to help out with these thus far. Those offers really do help, and I’ll be following up with everyone who’s made them, but the first mirror that lets us run our own virtual machine is most vital to our immediate needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your company &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; help, then please drop me an email at paul.j.fenwick at gmail, or you can tweet to me &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pjf&quot; class=&quot;social-link&quot;&gt;@pjf&lt;/a&gt;. We would &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you all so very much, and thank you in particular to all our amazing CKAN volunteers who have contributed to this success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(CKAN Project Founder)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/03/12/ckan-infrastructure-sponsor-needed.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/03/12/ckan-infrastructure-sponsor-needed.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Why non-code contributions matter</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Contributing to open source projects is often considered to be a good career move. Unlike doing work behind the closed doors of a proprietary business, contributions to open source provides visible proof of your skill and accomplishments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except that’s not always the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often the most visible contributions are &lt;em&gt;code&lt;/em&gt;. There’s an endless number of tools to graph, visualise, plot, and examine &lt;em&gt;code&lt;/em&gt; contributions. But software projects are not just code. The people who are doing user experience design and feedback isn’t coding. The people who are building a thriving community isn’t coding. The people triaging bugs, supporting the users, organising events, brainstorming ideas, acting as liaisons, and writing documentation are not coding. The people who notice when someone’s burning out and provide support; the people reminding contributors that they’re valued and doing a good job; the very people who are critical for the long term health of the project aren’t coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And often, they’re forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a poor situation for everyone involved. A lack of recognition means these vital people may leave the project, much to its detriment. The same lack of recognition means open source is not always a good career move, even when the work has been outstanding. It’s easy to see code metrics, but it’s much harder to point to non-code contributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something we need to fix. Non-code contributions come from a diverse range of backgrounds, much more diverse than code contributions. This means a lack of recognition is doubly bad for open source, not only are we failing to support vital contributions, but we’re also impeding diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leslie Hawthorn has written a brilliant piece on this¹, that goes into more detail, with better explanations than what I’ve written here. If you’re at all involved in open source, you should read it now. Most importantly, Leslie also provides a solution, and one that really should be obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acknowledge non-code contributions. Not just on mailing lists and support trackers, but in employer-visible locations such as LinkedIn, and across wider audiences such as social media. Leslie calls this “building the hat-rack”, although you’ll need to &lt;a href=&quot;http://hawthornlandings.org/2015/02/13/a-place-to-hang-your-hat/&quot;&gt;read her post&lt;/a&gt; to understand why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, I’m doing to do that right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish to say a very public thank you to Michele Ippolito, better known as “Ippo” in the Kerbal modding community. As some of you know, I started the CKAN project, a mod manager for Kebal Space Program. The CKAN has dozens of contributors, and has been a great success, and Ippo has been absolutely instrumental as part of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Ippo has a coding background, he’s been the linchpin of the CKAN &lt;em&gt;community&lt;/em&gt;. Ippo has spent countless hours liaising with mod authors, answering user queries, triaging bugs, writing documentation, maintaining the wiki, and making releases. If it were not for Ippo’s efforts, the CKAN simply wouldn’t be the resounding success that it is today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re involved in open source, or any field where contributions may go unacknowledged, I urge you to read Leslie’s post now and help acknowledge the amazing work that’s going on about you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With many thanks to everyone who’s building the future,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul #&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23LABHR&quot;&gt;LABHR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/02/15/why-non-code-contributions-matter.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/02/15/why-non-code-contributions-matter.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                     
	</channel>
</rss>
