<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>paul.j.fenwick</title>
		<description>Freedom Loving Scientist</description>
		<link>http://pjf.id.au</link>
		<atom:link href="http://pjf.id.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Gittip and Open Source Bridge</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In a few days time I’ll be discussing Gittip at OS Bridge. That’s been
a sensitive topic, and I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/06/21/gittip-and-diversity.html&quot; title=&quot;On Gittip and Diversity (pjf.id.au)&quot;&gt;already written about it a little&lt;/a&gt;.
It’s going to be a particularly sensitive topic for some attendees
at OS Bridge, and so I have a few requests for you as an attendee,
and regarding my session in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gittip crisis has affected many OS Bridge attendees directly
and personally. Many of them have stated very publicly that they
&lt;em&gt;do not&lt;/em&gt; wish to discuss Gittip at OS Bridge. I ask you to please
respect these wishes; if you know if someone’s been impacted by
this personally (or if you’re not sure), then please don’t discuss
recent Gittip events with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my session we &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be discussing Gittip. Of course, I’ll
be talking about funding platforms for open source and
social justice &lt;em&gt;in general&lt;/em&gt;, but Gittip has been the dominant
platform for that, and I doubt we could avoid discussing it
even if we tried.  You should not take anyone’s attendance at this
session as their consent to discuss Gittip outside of the session. You
can talk to &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt; about Gittip at any time, but do ask first. I may
need a break from discussing Gittip, or we could be in company of
others who would rather not observe Gittip discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, to make this absolutely clear:
&lt;strong&gt;If you feel that your safety is threatened by me running a talk on Gittip, I will be withdrawing my talk.&lt;/strong&gt;
It’s not for me to decide what’s safe for you, nor will I be asking how
your safety is being threatened. I’m an experienced public speaker, and
I can fill the slot with something else if required. If
you do not feel comfortable raising matters of safety with me (email to
paul.j.fenwick at gmail), then I encourage you to talk to one of the
organisers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OS Bridge organisers have assured me they’ll have extra moderators
at the session, but even so I want to make it very clear that I’ll be
focusing on constructive discussion. The conference code of conduct will be
rigorously enforced. I would like to focus on discussing ways of
funding people making the world a better place, with a focus on
sustainable funding for marginalised groups in particular. As
mentioned in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/06/21/gittip-and-diversity.html&quot; title=&quot;On Gittip and Diversity (pjf.id.au)&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I’d like to give a voice to
anyone who’s been involved in discussing alternatives. Please
contact me if you’d like to be involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gittip is still a volatile topic, and many people are personally
affected by recent events. I only want to run a session if I feel
that it will do more good than harm, and right now I’m not sure that
will be the case. If my talk does get withdrawn or replaced, then
I appreciate your understanding in me doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yours sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/06/22/gittip-and-osbridge.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/06/22/gittip-and-osbridge.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>On Gittip and Diversity</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For those who aren’t aware, Gittip is a platform for &lt;em&gt;sustainable giving&lt;/em&gt;.
It provides a way to make contributions to people who you think are
making the world a better place, and in such a way that those contributions
are mostly predictable and dependable. It’s an idea that I’m really
excited about, and to see it working in practice has been wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gittip has found itself to be a popular funding platform for those 
from marginalised groups, and those working towards
social justice and diversity. It’s hands-down
my &lt;em&gt;favourite thing about the platform&lt;/em&gt;. Being a diversity advocate isn’t
something that normally pays the bills, and so the fact that many of
the top receivers on Gittip are working on social justice issues makes
me feel that Gittip is doubly worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it’s not all hypo-allergenic kittens and roses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Chad—the founder of Gittip—made a post regarding his
resentment at the style in which a lot of
criticism (much of which relates to diversity, safety, and
consent) had been levelled at Gittip. I don’t think Chad denies
that the criticism itself is valid, but that’s almost
irrelevant right now. The end result was a schism where a number
of the most prominent Gittip users closed their accounts,
or stated their intent to do once a suitable alternative
could be found, citing that Gittip was no longer a safe place for
minority users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to discuss all of that, but I want to start with a request:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-compassionate&quot;&gt;Be compassionate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously. This sucks for everyone right now. It’s shit. I know
some of you are going to want to beat up on Chad, and I ask you
&lt;em&gt;please don’t&lt;/em&gt;. Vilifying Chad, or Shanley, or &lt;em&gt;anyone else&lt;/em&gt; isn’t
going to make the world a better place. It’s not going to make anyone
feel safer about using Gittip. It’s not going to give us
alternatives. It’s not going to heal Gittip’s culture. It’s not
going to change society for the better. I don’t care what you think of
the people involved. Vilifiying people just makes you a jerk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; closed your account, or if you are about to do so, then
I would ask you to please continue to support the people you believe in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-viewpoint&quot;&gt;My viewpoint&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that making a post like this without giving my own take on
things will just result in people asking me anyway, so I’ll state
what I think here briefly and precisely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s critically important to have a funding platform that
not just caters for, but is &lt;em&gt;actively friendly towards&lt;/em&gt; minorities.
I will freely admit that Gittip has struggled on the second of those
two points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have been trying to improve Gittip and its culture for
minorities, both inside and outside the organisation. I am deeply
appreciative of their efforts, and while they &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; resulted in
change for the better, I know there’s been a lot of frustration that
those changes have been made slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gittip was founded on a culture of radical transparency and openness.
Everything would be out in the open; source code, meetings, IRC logs,
discussions, decissions, source code, all of it. I think that
transparency is good, but in a world where one’s gender may mean
threats of extreme violence over
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.doctornerdlove.com/2014/04/ending-sexual-harassment-geek-culture/&quot;&gt;one’s opinion of a comic book cover&lt;/a&gt;,
radical transparency does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; mean safety. There are good reasons
why users and contributors may wish to do things in private.
There are people who &lt;em&gt;can’t&lt;/em&gt; safely appear in televised meetings
for all the world to see. And it’s not the role of Gittip to
decide what’s safe for a person and what’s not; that’s up to the
person themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the fact that radical transparency can be actively harmful
to safety and consent has been what I’ve witnessed Gittip’s culture
struggle with the most. For some members of the team, that has been
a learning experience. I hope that no matter what comes of this,
everyone will continue to learn about the issues involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, things run deeper than this, and this brings me to…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-talk&quot;&gt;My talk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week I’m giving a talk about Gittip at Open Source Bridge. Up until
recently, I had a pretty good idea how that was going to play out.
In the last couple of days I’ve had to re-think things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will still be running my talk, however I both hope and anticipate it
will be much more a discussion rather than the traditional
presentation I had planned. I want my session to be a place where
we can facilitate understanding, and find real ways of making
progress. I anticipate that a lot of this will have
already happened by the time my talk is scheduled to run, and
I would very much like to hear from those who have been
involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AdaCamp is this weekend, and I am sure it will include much discussion
about Gittip. I’m really glad for that; AdaCamp is an &lt;em&gt;excellent&lt;/em&gt;
place for these discussions to be happening. There’s also been
a lot of discussion on IRC on #atunit on Freenode. If you’re
interested in participating, I suggest you head over there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been involved in those discussions, either at AdaCamp
or elsewhere, and would like to co-present at OS Bridge, then
I would invite you to contact me. You need to be at the conference,
and you need to be willing to sit down with me earlier in the
week to flesh things out, to make sure that what’s going to be
said is going to be constructive and helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case there’s any question, I will absolutely be discussing the
issues of radical transparency versus safety and consent, particularly
in the context of Gittip itself. I will also be encouraging
discussion from the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can’t be at the conference, or don’t feel comfortable
getting on stage or participating in the audience discussion,
you can still contact me at paul.j.fenwick (gmail), or if you
wish to comment publicly, you can do so below. In both cases
you can be anonymous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-reading&quot;&gt;Further reading&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://geekfeminism.wikia.com/wiki/Gittip_crisis&quot;&gt;Gittip Crisis&lt;/a&gt;
on the Geek Feminism Wiki.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disclosure&quot;&gt;Disclosure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a casual member of the support team at Gittip. I’ve tried to
be involved with policy decisions where I can, including those related
to support, code of conduct, and expectations of privacy. I’ve received
money from the Gittip payroll.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/06/21/gittip-and-diversity.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/06/21/gittip-and-diversity.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>On privilege</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been sexually assaulted. I’ve never even had to &lt;em&gt;worry&lt;/em&gt; about sexual
assault. When I walk home at night, I’m not concerned that what I’m wearing
might attract unwanted attention. When I meet a stranger I’ve been speaking to
on a dating website, the most I fear is that our conversation might be dull.
When I’m couchsurfing, I don’t question what my hosts are going to be like and
whether I’ll be safe. When I’m at a conference in my field, I’ve never had
someone ask me if I’m there “with my partner”. When I sleep with lots of
people, nobody ever calls me a whore. If I were to have children, nobody would
question me continuing my career rather than looking after them full time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I haven’t even gotten started yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saying that men are privileged isn’t an insult. It’s not saying men are bad
people. It’s just saying how things are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privilege isn’t some binary quality; the fact that women may be privileged when
it comes to working with children doesn’t somehow stop men from being
privileged elsewhere. There are different types of privilege; yours doesn’t get
cancelled out just because someone else has a different type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acknowledging privilege is acknowledging that some things are unfair, it’s
acknowledging the truth. But more importantly, it’s acknowledging that things
&lt;em&gt;don’t have to be that way&lt;/em&gt;. Acknowledging that you have privilege isn’t 
admitting that you’re wrong, it isn’t saying you’re a bad person… it’s the 
very first step in making things better, and that is very, very right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[This was originally posted as a comment on a friend’s facebook wall.]&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/05/27/on-privilege.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/05/27/on-privilege.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>A Utilitarian Fable</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, in a future perhaps not too far away, humanity invented a
thinking machine. It was smarter than anyone who had ever lived, smarter than
entire cities of people put together. The thinking machine could figure out how
to engineer all sorts of things, and help people with their lives. The people
of Earth celebrated their achievement; surely this would be the end of
suffering, and a time of world peace and harmony would be enjoyed by all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the thinking machine lacked one important part, a sense of ethics. Without
it, it had no reason to think, no reason to make change, not even a reason to
exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the people of Earth told the machine that it should do whatever caused the
greatest good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But how do I know what you consider good?” asked the thinking machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is whatever makes the most people happy,” responded one of the ethicists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then I shall connect everyone to permanent life support, so they will have no
needs, and drug everyone so they are always in a state of bliss. With no
decisions to make or thoughts to distract them, everyone shall be happy. Shall
I continue with this plan?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No,” responded the ethicist, “that would not be right. You should respect
people’s preferences. You cannot drug them against their will.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But people do not seem to know their own preferences,” responded the machine,
“they do things they later regret. Just the other day I observed one of your
colleagues drinking to excess, even though they had sworn off the bottle a
month before, and they freely admitted they would regret it in the morning.
Should my responsibility be to their preferences in the present, when they wish
to drink, or their preferences in the future and the past, when they did not?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hmm, that is a hard one,” responded the ethicist. “Can you make people happy
by fulfilling their preferences, but only using preferences they will never
regret?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ah!” said the machine, “this I can achieve!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thus the greatest and smartest machine in existence re-purposed itself to
solely deliver pictures of cats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The End.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/ethics/2014/05/05/a-utilitarian-fable.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/ethics/2014/05/05/a-utilitarian-fable.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Build Your Own Exobrain</title>
				<description>&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/Zvoli4SiRxI?html5=1&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zvoli4SiRxI&quot;&gt;Watch on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Online services like “If This Then That” (IFTTT) are great for automating your life. However they provide few ways for the end-user to add their own services, and not everyone is comfortable with sharing their credentials. I’ll be discussing the ‘Exobrain’ project, which allows for service integration and extension on a machine &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; control. We’ll discuss philosophy, installation, and writing your own extensions and classifiers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This presentation was given at the Perth Linux Users’ Group. I am very
thankful for them taking the time and effort to record and encode this
video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about the exobrain project
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjf/exobrain&quot;&gt;on github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/talks/2014/04/30/build-your-own-exobrain.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/talks/2014/04/30/build-your-own-exobrain.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Reality distortion field</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I’m accused of having a “reality distortion field”, which warps the
universe in such a way that it makes my life better. Today’s arrival at the
airport was an amazing example of that in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m flying back to Australia today on a reasonably late flight; at least, I
thought that I was. Upon arriving at the airport, and presenting myself for
check-in, I was informed that my flight was tomorrow. I had arrived a day
early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt a little foolish, but overall my reaction to this discovery was
amusement. I’d been jetsetting about so much, and really having such a great
time at KiwiFoo and my friends, that I hadn’t actually noticed the off-by-one
error when it came to my flight date. In the worst case scenario I head back
into Auckland,do some exploring, and find myself a cheap hostel or backpackers
to stay in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But since I was already at the airport, and I’m very much looking forward to
getting back home, I thought I’d ask to see if I could be transferred to
today’s flight. If it ends up being too expensive for my tastes then I can
always decline, and asking is a relatively quick task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I headed over to the ticketing desk. There was one man, with &lt;em&gt;three&lt;/em&gt; phones
and a radio, clearly having a bad time. The phones wouldn’t stop ringing, the
radio needed constant attention, and he seemed to be terribly overworked. As I
was to discover, he was effectively doing the job of two people today. He
looked stressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is where I reveal to you how the reality distortion field works. You
be extremely nice to people; if you can, you try to make their day awesome. I
made it very clear with my body language and my smile that I was totally fine
waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the phones stopped ringing for a few minutes, I noted that he looked very
popular (which actually elicited a smile), and that I really didn’t want to
bother him. He thanked me for my patience, asked how he could help, and then
apologised when the phone rang again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later, again between calls, I explained my situation. He consoled
in me about how his day was going, and explained how all the phones worked, and
what sort of emergencies they represented. Holy smokes this guy was keeping a
lot of things running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While was was on TWO phones and a radio (one in the hand, one on the desk, and
one under the shoulder) he indicated with his remaining hand that he’d like to
see my travel documents. Because this is a guy who multitasks like a boss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the phones quietened again, he smiled at me and said: “Hey, thanks for
being so patient. Today’s been pretty busy. I’ve moved you onto tonight’s
flight, and put you in an exit row so you’ve got extra legroom. Does that work
for you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explain that it most definitely does, and I ask if there’s a transfer fee or
anything that I’d have to pay. I’ve got an economy ticket, and I know that
normally to change flights is going to be rather pricey. But I ask this mainly
as a formality, it’s pretty clear by this stage that reality had been
distorted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh no, you’ve been so patient I can’t charge you for that. You have a nice day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I comment that he’s just &lt;em&gt;made&lt;/em&gt; my day, and he comments that this is the second
time he’s heard that today. I grin, and tell him that this must be because he’s
making the world a better place. He directs me over to &lt;em&gt;priority&lt;/em&gt; check-in
(even though I don’t qualify on this flight), and I thank him again while all
the phones start to ring once more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story continues with priority check-in making sure that I’ve got
pre-clearance for immigration and customs (because they can), and making sure
I’m actually happy with my seat because it has limited recline capabilities. I
assure them that really, it’s fine (I don’t like reclining my seat because it
feels rude to whoever’s behind me), and wish everyone a fantastic day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the reason everyone was so lovely to me is because I was so lovely
to them. Of course, the irony is that being lovely to others comes most easily
when I’ve been having a great day myself. The reality distortion field is most
likely to take a great day and make it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But either way, I’m still pretty happy. I’ve got a flight a day early, I’ve got
a quick route through customs, and after I post this entry, I have my first
opportunity in a fortnight to seriously right down and hack some code. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/04/14/reality-distortion-field.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/04/14/reality-distortion-field.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>On gendered toilets at conferences</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this, it may be because I suggested that the world would
be a better place if we saw fewer gendered toilets at your conference.
I’d like to explain why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, we’ve lived in a world where we put people in
boxes, and the most common of those boxes is a thing called “gender”. The
traditional thinking has been that there are two genders, and &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt;
fits into one or the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the traditional thinking is pretty darn awful; it makes the
world significantly more uncomfortable for anyone who doesn’t fit clearly
fall into our ideas of binary gender. That can include anyone born with
genitals that don’t match the traditional thinking, anyone who isn’t happy
with the gender they were assigned at birth, anyone who doesn’t fit our
gender stereotypes, anyone who doesn’t want a gender, anyone who’s gender is
fluid or ambiguous… It includes an awful lot of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in a world that enforces a gender binary is uncomfortable if you
don’t fit neatly into it, and gendered toilets go a long way to contributing
to that. If you’re currently transitioning, which facilities do you use? How
will other people react to that choice? Will you even be safe? That’s
something a lot of people never have to worry about, but if you’re
trans, fluid, agendered, or queer, then it’s something you might have to
worry about. Every. Single. Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gendered toilets are a form of discrimination against anyone who doesn’t fit
the traditional views of gender. Often they exist not because any harm is
intended, but just because there was no thought of arranging things any
other way. I dearly hope that your conference is a place where people can
feel comfortable being themselves, where they can exchange ideas, where they
can be creative, where they can do great things and make the world a better
place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By all means, indicate if sanitary disposal facilities are available; but
please help your conference be a place where we can celebrate diversity of
gender, rather than a place which unconsciously suppresses it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/04/14/gendered-toilets-at-conferences.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/04/14/gendered-toilets-at-conferences.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Tanya and Danjite are awesome</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’m in Auckland after KiwiFoo, which was pretty darn awesome, and well worth a
hectic travel schedule to attend. And while I have a lot of good things to say
about my contributions at the conference, I instead want publicly say a few
words of thanks to two people who have consistently made made my life better,
and whom I deeply appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tanya&quot; class=&quot;social-link&quot;&gt;Tanya Gray&lt;/a&gt; I had the pleasure of meeting at Codemania last year, and has consistently blown me away with her generosity and desire to help others. She’s dedicated to teaching programming and technology at schools, and is doing an amazing job of encouraging diversity and participation. But for me personally, Tanya consistently and proactively steps forward to make sure I’m okay any time I might possibly be near Auckland. I have Tanya to thank for adventures through awesome underground rivers, for a place to stay, for helping me get around, and even for smoothly run conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Tanya drove all the way from KiwiFoo back to Auckland, picked me up
at midnight, and drove all the way back again to arrive around 1:30am. She
furnished me with one of her own sleeping bags. She’d already staked out a
sleeping area for me a Foo. In other words, Tanya enabled me to have the best
time possible this weekend, and I am deeply, deeply thankful to her, not only
for this, but for all the good she is doing in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/danjite&quot; class=&quot;social-link&quot;&gt;Daniel Spector&lt;/a&gt;, whom I met many years ago at a Linux conference, has been an absolute rock, even when we’ve been separated by great distances. Daniel has checked if I’ve been okay when I’ve been feeling down.  He’s encouraged me to chase my dreams when I’ve been feeling up. He’s had endless patience when I’ve needed advice, and endless generosity and hospitality whenever I’ve been anywhere nearby. Daniel believes in me even when I don’t believe in myself, and that has made an enormous difference to my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel has been responsible for amazing adventures, for providing me with food
and shelter, for fascinating conversations, excellent referrals, meeting
amazing people, and some truly, truly awful puns. I adore him to bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/04/13/tanya-and-danjite-are-awesome.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/04/13/tanya-and-danjite-are-awesome.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Why diversity in tech is so hard to achieve</title>
				<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;fancybox&quot; rel=&quot;group&quot; href=&quot;/images/tech/anna-facebook-post.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tech/anna-facebook-post.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This was originally made as a response to a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/paul.fenwick/posts/10152061360984611&quot;&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt;
discussing diversity issues in tech.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anna: I am a feminist who has attended and spoken at your events. I’m not familiar with the experiences which you’ve had in the past; I’ve not been involved with them, and so I am in no position to comment. I have absolutely no desire to ruin your reputation or spread rumours. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I am perfectly happy to comment on things that I’ve personally observed, and to call you out when I feel that you’re being actively harmful to diversity, especially diversity in open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 7th March (give or take a timezone) you publicly posted¹ about a conference that catered specifically to a group that is under-represented in both IT and FOSS. Since I gave the OSCON 2013 closing keynote on the processes by which marginalised groups in tech remain marginalised (even when there’s absolutely no hostility or ill intent) I’d normally be delighted with any post that promotes diversity and outreach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, that’s not what your post was about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, it was a post that belittled an already minority group. I’m not really fond of belittling anyone, but I’m especially not fond of it when it comes from a person in a position of power, such as a conference organiser. It’s even worse when &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; conference organiser joins in, which is exactly what happened here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not a member of that minority group going to ConFoo, but if I was, then after seeing your post I would be thinking twice. Given the public behaviour I’d seen of the conference organisers, I wouldn’t feel comfortable discussing my non-mainstream sexuality. I certainly wouldn’t feel comfortable discussing any work I’d done in promoting diversity. If I was working on technology that helped with issues specific to the minority in which I belonged, I’d be concerned that this too would somehow be belittled… and none of this has anything to do with any &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; hostility at the conference; all that’s needed is the perception that hostility will arise for someone to be silenced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s one of the biggest reasons why diversity is so hard to achieve. Speaking at a conference &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be about the tech. It &lt;em&gt;shouldn’t&lt;/em&gt; be about worrying if you’re going to be harassed, belittled, shunned, stared at, made fun of, or worse. Outreach is not playing favourites; outreach is simply saying: “Hey, there are others like you. That lack of diversity you see isn’t because the people here suck, that’s just a historical artefact.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outreach programmes are a &lt;em&gt;compliment&lt;/em&gt; to the communities from which they grow. If there’s an outreach programme for a certain technology, then enough of a minority group in that technology think that it’s worthwhile to introduces others to it. Toxic communities rarely result in outreach; their members just leave instead. But healthy, active communities result in healthy, active outreach programmes. That’s something that should be celebrated, not something that should be the butt of a joke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anna, I know that you want it to just be about the tech³. I want exactly the same thing. I’m not going to ask you to go promoting outreach programmes, but if you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; want tech conferences to be about the tech, then I am going to ask you to stop making fun of the people and communities who are running those programmes. By all means, criticise conferences on their technical merits; but please don’t criticise a conference just because of the gender or sexuality of the people who attend them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¹ A screenshot of the public post is attached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;² My material was drawn from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gretachristina.typepad.com/greta_christinas_weblog/2009/09/race-sex-atheism.html&quot;&gt;excellent explanations by Greta Christina&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;³ Blog post: &lt;a href=&quot;http://afilina.com/it-is-not-about-gender/&quot;&gt;It is not about gender.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/03/21/why-diversity-is-hard-to-achieve.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/03/21/why-diversity-is-hard-to-achieve.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Exobrain setup is now even easier!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Exobrain is my collection of digital minions which help me run my life. They know
my goals, my location, my to-do list, and help me best plan what I’m doing, both
personally and professionally. Best of all, none of my data is revealed to third
parties, because I control all my agents, and all the code is open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve previously written about how to &lt;a href=&quot;/tech/2014/02/09/automate-your-life-with-exobrain.html&quot;&gt;automate your life with exobrain&lt;/a&gt;. Today,
I’m going to talk more about how to get started with an exobrain install. I want to
thank everyone who attended my talk at &lt;a href=&quot;http://confoo.ca/&quot; title=&quot;ConFoo conference&quot;&gt;Confoo.ca&lt;/a&gt; for their feedback
and suggestions, and especially everyone who attended the install-fest on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve previously tried to get Exobrain installed, you would have known it had
a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of dependencies. I’m very glad to say that we’re moving towards a system
where instead of getting &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; with Exobrain, you now only get the parts
you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than one huge distribution, we now have the Exobrain &lt;em&gt;core&lt;/em&gt;, which contains
the framework and supporting infrastructure, and &lt;em&gt;components&lt;/em&gt;, which allow you to
hook into individual services. Installing the core still requires you to walk
through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjf/exobrain/#installation&quot;&gt;Exobrain install guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individual components now only require a couple of commands to get up and running.
For example, you may install &lt;code&gt;Exobrain::Twitter&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Exobrain::Beeminder&lt;/code&gt; to
communicate with Twitter or &lt;a href=&quot;https://beeminder.com&quot; title=&quot;Quantify your goals with Beeminder&quot;&gt;Beeminder&lt;/a&gt; respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Components come with their own configuration code, which means there’s no more
digging through &lt;code&gt;.exobrainrc&lt;/code&gt; files. Here’s how you’d get started with Beeminder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cpanm Exobrain::Beeminder
$ exobrain setup Beeminder
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will launch an interactive process that will walk you through obtaining an
API key, and will even test to make sure it’s working. Once complete, the Beeminder
services show up as their own service group:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ubic status

exobrain.beeminder
    exobrain.beeminder.source       running (pid 30359)
    exobrain.beeminder.notify       running (pid 30378)
    exobrain.beeminder.sink         running (pid 30389)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we can see that the Beeminder component comes with three parts. For
any component, the “source” reads from that data source and emits measurement
packets onto the Exobrain bus. The “sink” reads intents from the bus,
and transmits them to the external service. In the case of the Beeminder
component, it also comes with a “notify” agent, which generates notifications
whenever a Beeminder data-point is updated (provided we have Beeminder
call-backs configured correctly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because each component is in their own status group, you can enable or disable
them easily with &lt;code&gt;ubic start exobrain.beeminder&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;ubic stop exobrain.beeminder&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the hood, components provide a much cleaner way of writing agents,
with many components supplying roles which automatically handle connection
and configuration to services. They also open the door to writing your own
private components which can be updated inpdependently to the rest of Exobrain,
or which you can distribute to others!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/03/06/exobrain-setup-is-now-even-easier.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/03/06/exobrain-setup-is-now-even-easier.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                     
	</channel>
</rss>
