<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>paul.j.fenwick</title>
		<description>Some guy from the internet who loves freedom.</description>
		<link>http://pjf.id.au</link>
		<atom:link href="http://pjf.id.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Automate Your Life With Exobrain</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Services such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/&quot;&gt;If-This-Then-That&lt;/a&gt; (IFTTT) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com/&quot;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt; make it easy to connect apps and automate tedious tasks. However they all require you trust your personal data with a third party. Enter &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/pjf/exobrain&quot; title=&quot;Exobrain: A collection of agents which collect, classify, and act upon data&quot;&gt;Exobrain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exobrain is a free and open source framework for extending everything. It’s like IFTTT and Zapier, but you don’t have to reveal your credentials to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, Exobrain directly supports the following services:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://beeminder.com&quot; title=&quot;Quantify your goals with Beeminder&quot;&gt;Beeminder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Email/&lt;a href=&quot;https://gmail.com/&quot;&gt;Gmail&lt;/a&gt; (via IMAP)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://foursquare.com/&quot;&gt;Foursquare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://habitrpg.com/&quot; title=&quot;Level up your life with HabitRPG&quot;&gt;HabitRPG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://idonethis.com/&quot; title=&quot;Measure your progress with iDoneThis&quot;&gt;iDoneThis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pushover.net/&quot; title=&quot;Pushover: Simple mobile notifications&quot;&gt;Pushover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rememberthemilk.com/&quot; title=&quot;RememberTheMilk task tracker&quot;&gt;RememberTheMilk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Beeminder users, Exobrain also supports call-backs. This means you can chain events off anything that Beeminder can measure, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.withings.com/en/scales/&quot;&gt;Withings&lt;/a&gt; scales, &lt;a href=&quot;http://runkeeper.com/&quot;&gt;Runkeeper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fitbit.com/&quot;&gt;fitbit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rescuetime.com/&quot;&gt;RescueTime&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.duolingo.com/&quot;&gt;duolingo&lt;/a&gt;, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a quantified-selfer, you can automatically record your activities to your log. If you need some extra motivation, you can automatically gain experience points on &lt;a href=&quot;https://habitrpg.com/&quot;&gt;HabitRPG&lt;/a&gt; for achieving your goals. You can back-up all of your activity from third-party websites in real-time, or even allow people to add to your TODO list by tweeting at you with a &lt;code&gt;#todo&lt;/code&gt; tag!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own a &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpebble.com/&quot;&gt;Pepple watch&lt;/a&gt; and are a Pushover user, then you can send notifications directly to your watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use pre-written Exobrain actions or you can write your own. Exobrain is completely free, open source, and extensible. Because it uses a shared message bus, you can even update components on the fly, without having to restart the whole system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exobrain is written in Perl and at its core uses an extensible, language-independent, messaging format based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://zeromq.org/&quot;&gt;0MQ&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.json.org/&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing extensions for Exobrain is easy; here’s the entire code to send all tweets that mention you to your preferred notify service:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='perl'&gt;    &lt;span class='c1'&gt;#!/usr/bin/env perl&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='k'&gt;use&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;Exobrain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class='nv'&gt;$exobrain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;watch_loop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='n'&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;#39;Measurement::Tweet&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='n'&gt;filter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='k'&gt;sub &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nv'&gt;$_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;to_me&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='p'&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='k'&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='k'&gt;sub &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class='nv'&gt;$exobrain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;notify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nv'&gt;$_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;summary&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='p'&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='p'&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='p'&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exobrain is very much a work-in-progress, and we would love your contributions and feedback. You can find &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjf/exobrain&quot;&gt;Exobrain on github&lt;/a&gt;. Contributions to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjf/exobrain/issues&quot;&gt;issues list&lt;/a&gt; are especially appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au//tech/2014/02/09/automate-your-life-with-exobrain.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au//tech/2014/02/09/automate-your-life-with-exobrain.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Remembering Aaron Swartz</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a little over a year since Aaron Swartz passed by taking his own life. Aaron was a hero of the Internet. He believed strongly in freedom and privacy. He was instrumental in helping retain freedom and privacy on the Internet. He fought for civil liberties and social justice. He made the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that for many people, the thought of mass surveillance, of warrantless wiretapping, seems abstract and remote. That’s one of the reasons why it’s so insidious; by its very nature we don’t see it happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following video is part of a campaign that I believe strongly about. Whether you choose to participate, or learn more, is entirely up to you. But the video itself is a beautiful testament to Aaron’s life, and changes for good that he made in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='video-container'&gt;&lt;iframe height='420' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/RJ194S7KjRg?html5=1' width='560'&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RJ194S7KjRg'&gt;Watch on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://thedaywefightback.org/&quot;&gt;The Day We Fight Back&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au//personal/2014/02/07/remembering-aaron-swartz.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au//personal/2014/02/07/remembering-aaron-swartz.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Tolerance, not bigotry, now maximises shareholder value</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Coca-Cola showed an advertisement as part of the superbowl coverage. It featured Americans doing American things; except those Americans were racially diverse, and the song—America The Beautiful—was sung in multiple languages other than English.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a big deal on the Internet right now about the bigotry and hatred which this advertisement has revealed. Of course Coke knew this would happen, and yet they screened the advertisement anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason is simple. As a society, we’re becoming &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; tolerant every year, and Coca-Cola knows that. It’s firmly directing its ad towards the growing and more ethical population who believes that diversity and tolerance are good, rather than the shrinking percentage of people who do not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We, as a society, are getting better. Yes, you can pick apart Coke’s motives here, but the fact remains that we’re now in a society where promoting diversity and tolerance are seen as winning strategies. That’s not something we would have seen fifty years ago, and I doubt it’s even something we would have seen ten years back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still have a long way to go, but we’re getting there. Thank you, humanity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au//ethics/2014/02/04/tolerance-now-maximises-sharehold-value.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au//ethics/2014/02/04/tolerance-now-maximises-sharehold-value.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>One Thing Can Make The World A Better Place</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Many people have the dream of being a successful writer. There’s an allure with having one’s work read by others, but the business of writing has changed. One no longer seeks a publisher, but instead traffic and results on search engines. One no longer expects royalties, instead revenue is generated from advertisements and affiliate links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The language of the web is now monetization. If that were my goal there’d be advertisements on this website. But there are none. At least, not in the form you’d expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;figure class='right smaller'&gt;&lt;a class='fancybox' href='/images/ethics/toilet-cat.jpg' rel='group'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/ethics/toilet-cat.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Smiling at a cat still brings good to the world.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s commonplace at to prompt the reader to stick around at the end of one’s article. But my goal isn’t to have others read my writing, that’s merely a means to an end. My goal is to &lt;em&gt;make the world a better place&lt;/em&gt;, and I hope to co-opt my readers into helping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So at the end of every article, I’d like to direct the reader to whatever will bring the greatest good. That could be something as simple as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PKffm2uI4dk&quot;&gt;funny cat video&lt;/a&gt;; after all, making people smile &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; bringing good to the world. But I think we can do better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presently, I’m encouraging people to read &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1bABN6P&quot;&gt;3 myths that block progress for the poor&lt;/a&gt; after &lt;a class='social-link' href='https://twitter.com/Quintrino'&gt;@Quintrino&lt;/a&gt; brought it to my attention. It’s an incredible piece; well-written and researched. If you have the time, I strongly encourage you to read and share it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However my most popular article has to do with how &lt;a href=&quot;/ethics/2014/01/25/how-to-screw-learning-with-one-simple-belief.html&quot;&gt;beliefs can influence learning&lt;/a&gt;, with over 35,000 hits in the last five days. I have evidence that it’s particularly popular with parents, so at this very moment time &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; are my target audience. However I’m interested in &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; suggestions as to what I can encourage readers to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that one thing &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; know which will make the world a better place… what is it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please scroll down and add your suggestion in the comments below; you can be anonymous if you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au//ethics/2014/01/31/one-thing-can-make-the-world-a-better-place.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au//ethics/2014/01/31/one-thing-can-make-the-world-a-better-place.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>I have a favour to ask.</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Dear everyone, I have a favour to ask…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine the future. Not as it is next week, next year, or even in a hundred years hence. Imagine the future as it exists in &lt;em&gt;ten thousand&lt;/em&gt; years time; and imagine that’s a future where things have gone &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not a dystopia; humanity has gone beyond its roots and has colonised the stars. We’ve outgrown our humble beginnings, we’ve overcome the flaws in our brain: anger, jealousy, selfishness; but we’ve kept the things which are important. We have compassion, and foresight. We have understanding, and ethics. I want you to imagine the &lt;em&gt;best possible future&lt;/em&gt; that you can; one that’s not just best for humanity, but also best for any being that may be able to think or feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a big leap of imagination, but I want you to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I want you to do something in the next 24 hours—purposefully and consciously, regardless of how big or small—which would make our future selves &lt;em&gt;proud&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can share that here if you like. You can keep it to yourself. It can be a tiny tiny thing, or it can be the crowning achievement of your existence. But it’s human nature to think about the here-and-now, and I so dearly, dearly wish we’d spend more time working towards how things &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au//ethics/2014/01/30/one-favour.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au//ethics/2014/01/30/one-favour.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>How to learn everything, without spending any time</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;What if I told you there’s an app which runs on all your devices, is free, has strong evidence-based support for its effectiveness, and allows you to acquire large amounts of knowledge and &lt;em&gt;retain it indefinitely&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if I told you it wasn’t even going to take any time out of your day?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;figure class='right'&gt;&lt;a class='fancybox' href='/images/tech/anki.png' rel='group'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/tech/anki.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Anki: It's like having cheat-codes for knowledge.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two amazing tools which I use during those odd chunks of time. The first &lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/01/23/dont-read-articles--listen-to-them.html&quot; title=&quot;Don't read articles, listen to them (pjf.id.au)&quot;&gt;reads me articles I’ve saved&lt;/a&gt;, and requires only that I have headphones. The second is &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankisrs.net/&quot; title=&quot;Anki: Powerful, intelligent flashcards&quot;&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s like having cheat-codes for knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki is a flash-card system that employs &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacing_effect&quot; title=&quot;Spacing Effect (Wikipedia)&quot;&gt;spaced repetition&lt;/a&gt;, which exploits our understanding of human memory to allow you to obtain a large amount of knowledge, and then &lt;em&gt;retain that knowledge indefinitely&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know from research that we remember things most &lt;em&gt;efficiently&lt;/em&gt; when we’re tested infrequently over a longer time span. If you’ve ever crammed for an exam, you’ve probably discovered you’ve lost that knowledge a week or two later. Anki and spaced repetition gives us &lt;em&gt;anti-cramming&lt;/em&gt;, letting you do a minimum of work to memorize information over a long period of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The working behind spaced repetition is simple. As long as you’re able to keep remembering, the time between successive tests gradually increases. New knowledge may be tested multiple times per week, but things you know really well will may come up every couple of years. The idea is to get you to recall knowledge just before you’re about to forget it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provided you practice regularly, it’s possible to learn and retain a tremendous amount of information. Regular practice sounds like it’s going to be hard, but I’ve discovered it’s actually the easiest part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My day is full of odd bits of time that aren’t typically useful. Waiting for a tram, for my coffee to brew, standing in line at the airport. These chunks aren’t long enough to do much with, but they’re &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; for Anki cards. Each card takes only a few seconds, and if you reach your learning goals for the day there are always options to review ahead. Because you’re recycling time that would otherwise be wasted, using Anki comes with practically no opportunity costs whatsoever!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Anki phone app comes with the ability to configure notifications if you have cards due. &lt;em&gt;Switch that on&lt;/em&gt;. Simply having an icon on your toolbar provides a reminder you’ve got cards to complete, and can help act as a visual cue for whenever you open up your phone and wonder what you were meant to be doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki lets you make your own decks in the desktop client. I have decks for words I frequently misspell, dietary intolerances of my friends, people I’ve met, &lt;a href=&quot;https://coursera.org/&quot; title=&quot;Coursera: Take free online classes from 80+ top universities and organisations&quot;&gt;subjects I’ve learning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://duolingo.com/&quot; title=&quot;Duolingo: Learn languages for free&quot;&gt;languages&lt;/a&gt;, and anything else that I know I’ll easily forget. However Anki also has a rich number of &lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/decks/&quot; title=&quot;Anki Shared Decks&quot;&gt;shared decks&lt;/a&gt;. For me personally, both &lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/970971960&quot;&gt;cognitive biases&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ankiweb.net/shared/info/1530243698&quot;&gt;hiragana/katakana&lt;/a&gt; (Japanese characters) feature heavily in my learning schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anki has clients for Windows, Mac, Linux/BSD, iOS, and Android; as well as a mobile-friendly web interface. While the iOS client requires payment, the others are free and open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what are you waiting for? &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankisrs.net/&quot; title=&quot;Anki: Powerful, intelligent flashcards&quot;&gt;Download Anki&lt;/a&gt; and start learning!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au//tech/2014/01/29/learn-everything-without-spending-time.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au//tech/2014/01/29/learn-everything-without-spending-time.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Don't read social media</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;My advice for you today is &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; read social media. Most of it is rubbish, and there’s a good chance you’re only reading it because you’re bored. If you’re actively engaged, then fine, but if you’ve just spent the last 30 minutes listlessly flicking through posts, then stop that. Stop it right now. You’re not making yourself any happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know how you’ve got that thing you enjoy, but which takes more time and effort? Go do that instead. I don’t care if it’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/&quot; title=&quot;Project Gutenberg: Over 42,000 free ebooks&quot;&gt;reading&lt;/a&gt;, or painting, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecademy.com/&quot; title=&quot;CodeAcademy: Learn to code&quot;&gt;coding&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://writtenkitten.net/&quot; title=&quot;Written? Kitten!&quot;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://duolingo.com/&quot; title=&quot;Duolingo: Learn languages for free&quot;&gt;learning a language&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://coursera.org/&quot; title=&quot;Coursera: Take free online classes from 80+ top universities and organisations&quot;&gt;studying&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fitocracy.com/&quot; title=&quot;Fitocracy: The fitness social network to level up in real life&quot;&gt;exercise&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://hpmor.com/&quot; title=&quot;Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality&quot;&gt;whatever&lt;/a&gt;. Go do that now. If your brain is fried, then go &lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/01/23/dont-read-articles--listen-to-them.html&quot; title=&quot;Don't read articles, listen to them (pjf.id.au)&quot;&gt;listen to articles&lt;/a&gt;, discover &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Spoken_articles&quot; title=&quot;Spoken Wikipedia&quot;&gt;spoken wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, or y’know, actually sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But please—unless you have &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anhedonia&quot; title=&quot;Anhedonia (Wikipedia)&quot;&gt;anhedonia&lt;/a&gt;—don’t spend your time bored and listlessly scrolling through posts on social media. There’s so much more you could be doing instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au//personal/2014/01/28/my-advice-for-today.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au//personal/2014/01/28/my-advice-for-today.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>How to screw learning with one simple belief</title>
				<description>&lt;figure class='right'&gt;&lt;a class='fancybox' href='/images/ethics/praise-fail.png' rel='group'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/ethics/praise-fail.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Source: Mueller and Dweck¹&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This. Right here. Look at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a graph showing the performance of children after they’ve been praised for their intelligence (“you must be smart”) versus their effort (“you must have put a lot of effort into that”), and then given a series of hard problems to try to solve. The kids who are taught that effort count &lt;em&gt;increase&lt;/em&gt; in the number of problems they can solve. Those who are told that they’re smart show a frightening decrease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the difference? Those being told that they’re smart are taught that abilities are fixed. If you’re finding a puzzle hard, then it must be because you’re not very good at that, and you should try something else. Kids taught that results are based on effort see the hard puzzles as something they can &lt;em&gt;learn&lt;/em&gt; to do, and then they do so¹.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class='right'&gt;&lt;a class='fancybox' href='/images/ethics/praise-preference.png' rel='group'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/ethics/praise-preference.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Source: Mueller and Dweck¹&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is shown really clearly in the second graph. Children are asked what type of puzzles they’d like to solve, and are given four options. The first three are pretty similar: “problems that aren’t too hard, so I don’t get many wrong,” “problems that are pretty easy, so I’ll do well,” and “problems that I’m pretty good at, so I can show that I’m smart.” However the last option is different: “problems that I’ll learn a lot from, even if I won’t look so smart.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first three options are “performance” options, they’re all about looking good, or getting things right. The last option is a “learning” option, and it values knowledge and growth over performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second graph shows how often children selected performance options based upon the type of praise they were given. Children praised for their intelligence choose tasks which are easy and make them look good; children praised for their effort choose tasks which are hard, and which will teach them more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is important enough, but there are social ramifications as well. People with more fixed views of ability are more likely to adopt stereotypes, and are less likely to develop to higher levels of ethical reasoning than those with dynamic views of ability². And this doesn’t seem to have a damn thing to do with cognitive abilities; it’s all about outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not go through life believing that you lack a talent, and do not allow others to believe that about themselves. Humans have an amazing capacity for growth; learning is hard, but it’s &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¹ Mueller, Claudia M., and Carol S. Dweck. “Praise for Intelligence Can Undermine Children’s Motivation and Performance.” Journal of Personality and Social Psychology 75, no. 1 (1998): 33. [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uky.edu/~eushe2/mrg/MuellerDweck1998.pdf&quot;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;² Levy, Sheri R., and Carol S. Dweck. “The Impact of Children’s Static versus Dynamic Conceptions of People on Stereotype Formation.” Child Development 70, no. 5 (1999): 1163–1180. [&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stanford-knowledgebase.org/dept/psychology/cgi-bin/drupalm/system/files/Children%27s%20static%20vs%20dynamic%20person%20conceptions%20as%20predictors%20of%20their%20stereotype%20information.pdf&quot;&gt;pdf&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au//ethics/2014/01/25/how-to-screw-learning-with-one-simple-belief.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au//ethics/2014/01/25/how-to-screw-learning-with-one-simple-belief.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Don't read articles, listen to them</title>
				<description>&lt;figure class='right smaller'&gt;&lt;a class='fancybox' href='/images/tech/pocket.png' rel='group'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/tech/pocket.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I pottered around the kitchen. I made toast and coffee, I washed the dishes, I sorted my groceries. I also read a lengthy article on AIDS in China at the same time. In fact, I’ve been reading more than ever now that I’ve given up on actually &lt;em&gt;reading&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t hide the fact that I want to learn everything. I have &lt;a href=&quot;http://ankisrs.net/&quot; title=&quot;Anki: Powerful, intelligent flashcards&quot;&gt;flashcards&lt;/a&gt; that I practice every day, I’m enrolled in more &lt;a href=&quot;https://coursera.org/&quot; title=&quot;Coursera: Take free online classes from 80+ top universities and organisations&quot;&gt;coursera&lt;/a&gt; courses than I can poke a stick at, and my most favourite thing in the world is to find someone with specialised knowledge and enthusiasm and talk to them about it in depth. Consequently, I do a lot of thinking about how to learn efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing which is very apparent to me is that I have limited resources when it comes to concentration. If I’m having a conversation, or writing an article, or hacking code, then that concentration slot is full; I can’t do anything else that requires much cognition at the same time. It’s concentration that’s my limited resource when it comes to learning and creating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, there are so many times each day when I’m &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; concentrating on something, and yet have the capacity to do so. Public transport, making breakfast, even sitting on the loo. Sometimes those times are used for serious thinking, but often they’re just filled with frivolous or even anxious thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a good solution to this. And for me, it’s been game-changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a free app called &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpocket.com/&quot; title=&quot;Pocket: Save for later. Put articles, videos or pretty much anything into Pocket.&quot;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;. It takes articles, turns them into a format that looks great on mobile devices, and syncs them so you can read them anywhere. That’s nice; but by itself it still means I need to have my phone out to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clincher is that Pocket for Android comes with built-in text-to-speech (TTS) capabilities. If you combine it with a TTS engine that doesn’t suck, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ivona.com/&quot; title=&quot;IVONA: Award winning, natural text-to-speech for desktop, mobile, server and web.&quot;&gt;Ivona&lt;/a&gt; immediately springs to mind here, then you have a &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; easier way of “reading” articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The combination is so nice that I read articles almost exclusively via Pocket and Ivona now. I’m even adding &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/pjf/exobrain&quot; title=&quot;Exobrain: A collection of agents which collect, classify, and act upon data&quot;&gt;exobrain&lt;/a&gt; capabilities sending me an article on social media will automatically add it to my reading queues. Of course, all my writing on &lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/&quot; title=&quot;Paul Fenwick's personal website&quot;&gt;pjf.id.au&lt;/a&gt; sounds great in Pocket, too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, Pocket for iOS lacks the built-in TTS capabilities; I’ve been told iOS lacks an easy-to-use speech interface for developers. However many third-party apps seem to have sprung up to fill this niche. If you have any good experiences, I’d love to hear about them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au//tech/2014/01/23/dont-read-articles--listen-to-them.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au//tech/2014/01/23/dont-read-articles--listen-to-them.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Automated backups with udev and btrfs</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’m incredibly lazy. My preferred way of making backups is to plug in an external drive, and have my laptop automatically do the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to facilitate this laziness, I’m going to be using two tools: btrfs (an amazing filesystem with snapshot support), and udev (which can detect when a device has been inserted or removed). I’m also going to send notifcations directly to my Pebble watch, because I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything in this guide needs to be done as root, so we might as well start a root-shell now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ sudo -i&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;preparing_our_disk&quot;&gt;Preparing our disk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2014/01/bitrot-and-atomic-cows-inside-next-gen-filesystems/&quot; title=&quot;Bitrot and atomic COWs: Inside next-gen filesystems&quot;&gt;btrfs&lt;/a&gt; for external backups. It’s able to detect when data has gone bad, it has wicked-cool snapshot capabilities, and if I’m backing up an existing btrfs filesystem I can do very quickly and efficiently by sending incremental snapshots. However most of this guide will still work even if you’re using a different filesystem type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first step is to prepare the disk where our backups are going to live. under Linux we can have volumes with &lt;em&gt;labels&lt;/em&gt;. They’re awesome, because they’re human readable, but still provide a way to identify a device regardless of where it gets mounted. In theory one could have a number of drives with the same label, and we could trigger a backup automatically whenever &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; of them are plugged in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With btrfs, we can set the label when we format the disk, but I always forget to do that. It’s okay, because changing the label is easy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ btrfs filesystem label /dev/sdc1 backup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re using &lt;code&gt;ext2&lt;/code&gt; or above, you can do the same with &lt;code&gt;tune2fs&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ tune2fs -L backup /dev/sdc1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My actual disks have more descriptive labels, indicating both the machine and filesystem they’re responsible for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to mount my backups in a consistent location, so I’m going to create that now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ mkdir /mnt/backup&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also need to tell linux that when it sees a disk with the &lt;code&gt;backup&lt;/code&gt; label, it needs to go on the mount-point specified. We do this by adding a line to &lt;code&gt;/etc/fstab&lt;/code&gt;, and we can also specify other options in here as well For example, I use btrfs’ compression option:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ echo &amp;quot;LABEL=backup /mnt/backup btrfs noauto,compress 0 2&amp;quot; \
    &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/fstab&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On other filesystems, you should leave out ‘compress’ on the line above. The ‘noauto’ option tells Linux not to try and mount the drive when booting; as a removable backup drive, it’s unlikely to be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;udev&quot;&gt;udev&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the bit which caused me pain, &lt;code&gt;udev&lt;/code&gt;, a system for triggering events when devices change on your system. I don’t know if there are versions of &lt;code&gt;udev&lt;/code&gt; with different keywords, or which care differently about capitalisation, but it took a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of tweaking around until I managed to get a udev rule that would automatically mount my disk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cat &amp;gt; /etc/udev/rules.d/99-backup.rules

SUBSYSTEM==&amp;quot;block&amp;quot;, ENV{ID_FS_LABEL}==&amp;quot;backup&amp;quot;, ACTION==&amp;quot;add&amp;quot;, \
    RUN+=&amp;quot;/bin/mount /mnt/backup&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Udev is also supposed to automatically pick up new rules, but my system didn’t the first time. We can nudge it with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ udevadm control --reload-rules&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;backups&quot;&gt;Backups&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make backups I’m using rsync. I use both &lt;code&gt;ionice&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;nice&lt;/code&gt; to have our command yield both io and cpu resources to other processes, so we don’t lose system responsiveness during the backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also use the &lt;code&gt;-vHAaxX&lt;/code&gt; switches to &lt;code&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt;. This backups up &lt;code&gt;v&lt;/code&gt;erbosely, &lt;code&gt;H&lt;/code&gt;ard links, &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt;CLs, &lt;code&gt;a&lt;/code&gt;ll, &lt;code&gt;X&lt;/code&gt;tended attributions, and sticking to one filesystem (&lt;code&gt;-x&lt;/code&gt;). I also pass in &lt;code&gt;--delete&lt;/code&gt; to remove files from the backup drive that are no longer on my machine’s disk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I also pass &lt;code&gt;--filter 'P SNAPSHOT-*&lt;/code&gt;, to tell rsync to protect any file at the destination which starts with &lt;code&gt;SNAPSHOT-&lt;/code&gt;. As we’ll see in a moment, these are my btrfs snapshots; we don’t want rsync to try and remove them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ionice -c3 nice rsync -vHAaxX --delete \
    --filter 'P SNAPSHOT-*' / /mnt/backup/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this is done (it can take some time), I take a read-only btrfs snapshot on my backup drive with the current date in UTC:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ btrfs subvolume snapshot -r /mnt/backup \
    /mnt/backup/SNAPSHOT-`date -u +%Y-%m-%d`&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the joys of btrfs is the top-level filesystem on my backup drive is arranged exactly the same way as the filesystem I’m backing up. In a pinch I could use it a a drop-in replacement. If a file doesn’t change between snapshots, then btrfs requires no additional storage space to store it, and with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/g2p/bedup&quot; title=&quot;bedup: btrfs de-duplication&quot;&gt;bedup&lt;/a&gt; we can even de-duplicate files across filesystems and subvolumes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each snapshot is also a complete backup in its own right; I never have to worry about whether I have a base filesystem upon which to apply an incremental backup on to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not using btrfs or a similar snapshotting filesystem, you might find &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rsnapshot.org/&quot; title=&quot;rsnapshot: A remote filesystem snapshot utility, based on rsync&quot;&gt;rsnapshot&lt;/a&gt; preferable to straight rsync. It makes rolling snapshots where unchanged files are hard linked to conserve space, but looks like a complete backup each time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;automating_everything_with_snapback&quot;&gt;Automating everything with snapback&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Snapback&lt;/code&gt; is some code I wrote because anything more than plugging in a USB drive to my laptop is just too much work. It uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://pushover.net/&quot; title=&quot;Pushover: Simple mobile notifications&quot;&gt;Pushover&lt;/a&gt; to send notifications to my pebble watch, so there’s no need to look through &lt;code&gt;/var/log&lt;/code&gt; to see what’s happening, and I’m immediately notified when the backup is complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It ties all the above together into a script that’s triggered from udev. Because udev kills any process that’s running too long, under the hood we fork a daemon to do the heavy lifting for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Snapback&lt;/code&gt; is pretty heavily customised to work on my laptop, but you’re welcome to adapt it to your own purposes if you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjf/snapback&quot; title=&quot;Snapback: Automatically backup your machine to btrfs when a disk is plugged in (GitHub)&quot;&gt;find snapback on github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;credits&quot;&gt;Credits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a class='social-link' href='https://twitter.com/jeremyvisser'&gt;Jeremy Visser&lt;/a&gt; for pointing out &lt;code&gt;sudo -i&lt;/code&gt; as a more comfortable way to get a root shell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a class='social-link' href='https://twitter.com/evmcl'&gt;Evan&lt;/a&gt; for reminding me of rsnapshot, and providing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/evmcl/pjf.github.io/commit/fa400560eb9aabf14b9d324b462ea58ddba3ddc4&quot;&gt;content patch&lt;/a&gt; to this article! :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au//tech/2014/01/23/automated-backups-with-udev-and-btrfs.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au//tech/2014/01/23/automated-backups-with-udev-and-btrfs.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                     
	</channel>
</rss>
