<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>paul.j.fenwick</title>
		<description>Freedom Loving Scientist</description>
		<link>http://pjf.id.au</link>
		<atom:link href="http://pjf.id.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Seeking a humanitarian FOSS outreach position</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In 2017 I spent some time working with the United Nationals Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs (UN-OCHA). While I developed a number of software tools in that role, what made me &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; effective was the fact that I could develop everything open source. The amount of advice, pull-requests, and feedback that I enthusiastically received from public experts was tremendous, and I’m sure that this was helped in no small part by the fact that I was working for a high-profile humanitarian organisation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since then, I’ve been thinking. What if I could do humanitarian open source outreach as a job?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s tremendous appeal to me for a paid outreach position; not only am I able to deliver more value than I could on my own, but there’s also opportunities for me to learn, to teach, to further the careers of others, and to build communities. While I’ve been privately offered positions as a developer evangelist at a number of companies, working in the humanitarian space is &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; more in line with &lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/ethics/2015/08/20/im-donating-10pc-of-my-income-to-charity.html&quot;&gt;my values&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve a lot that would qualify me for this role. I’ve been writing and speaking about open source for decades. I’ve launched and managed numerous successful open source projects in the past, the largest of which—the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/KSP-CKAN&quot;&gt;Comprehensive Kerbal Archive Network&lt;/a&gt;—has hundreds of contributors and hundreds of thousands of users. I thoroughly enjoy knowledge exchange of all sorts. And finally I’m also a prominent public speaker, especially able to draw a large audience when it comes to technical and social matters. Alongside many technical talks, I’ve also I’ve given presentations on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xuK6udkbyGo&quot;&gt;open source and humanitarian efforts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nEC9qMvnOh0&quot;&gt;mental health&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.realm.io/posts/try-swift-nyc-2017-paul-fenwick-machine-ethics-emerging-technology/&quot;&gt;whether technology is making the world a better place&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course such a role would not be without its challenges. Structuring a project to maximise contributions and community growth often involves using different tools and methodologies than would be used for an internal project. My schedule tends to be choppy, as I travel a lot for conferences, but this also means I’m able to do more outreach as I go. I’m based in Australia, which can present its own time coordination challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ideal role would be be half to three-quarter time, based in Melbourne or remotely, and would have me developing—and most importantly helping others develop—open source tools in the humanitarian sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you think that you’ve got something that’s up my alley, then drop me an email at paul.j.fenwick@gmail.com, or catch me at OSCON this year, I’d love to hear from you! My resume is available upon request.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2018/07/17/foss-outreach.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2018/07/17/foss-outreach.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>I Have Bipolar—An Open Letter</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I was diagnosed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bipolar_II_disorder&quot;&gt;type II bipolar&lt;/a&gt;, and while some of you who know me might feel that was obvious, it was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; obvious to me. I want to talk about what the diagnosis means, what it’s like to have Bipolar II, and the effect my medications are having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- read more --&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-its-like-to-have-bipolar&quot;&gt;What it’s like to have bipolar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s a common belief that people with bipolar have two mood poles that they swing between. They’re either up or down. They’re either manic or depressed. And you’d be forgiven for thinking that, because it’s absolutely what &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; thought up until the point of my diagnosis. However I can tell you from first-hand experience that this is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having bipolar means having has two &lt;em&gt;axes&lt;/em&gt;. There’s the manic axis, and the depression axis, and it’s possible to be on both of them at the &lt;em&gt;same time&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone with bipolar, being depressed is the big thing which most feels like a mental illness. My depressive moods would come on very suddenly; it would feel like I’d have a normal response to sadness,but then there’d be a &lt;em&gt;cliff&lt;/em&gt; that I would just tumble off and into despair. I’d actually describe these periods as being in a “pit of despair”, and I really did feel like I was in some sort of pit. Everything would be hard, nothing seemed to be worth it, and not only could I not feel joy, I couldn’t even imagine feeling joy in the future. My pits would often come with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psychomotor_retardation&quot;&gt;psychomotor retardation&lt;/a&gt;, where I would lay still and my thoughts would slow to a crawl. Oddly enough, that was the only thing I &lt;em&gt;liked&lt;/em&gt; about my pits. Everything felt awful, but if I got far enough down I didn’t have to experience the full weight of consciousness. It was oddly comforting in a way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes my brain would be sad for no reason. I’d feel awful, everything would seem grey, but there’d be no reason for this. Sometimes I would &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; something was making me feel bad, like the current state of information security, or how we’re screwing up with climate change, but honestly my brain was just not being kind to me. These would be the days when I’d struggle to get out of bed. Oddly enough, these were also some of the days when I did my best writing, but that writing was never about joyous things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My manic episodes, on the other hand, &lt;em&gt;didn’t&lt;/em&gt; feel like part of an illness. Bipolar II means my manic episodes are “hypomanic”, they’re not full-blown mania. I don’t lose touch with reality or purchase cryptocurrencies, but I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; become very outgoing and very productive. A lot of you have probably met me or interacted with me in my hypomanic states. I’m filled with ideas, conversation comes to me easily, and I can absolutely throw myself at whatever project I currently have on hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking that my manic episodes sound enjoyable, they are. Most of my large accomplishments were done in a manic state. Writing the KSP-CKAN was &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; done during a bout of mania. I’d joke that “I thought we needed a mod manager, so five weeks and 300 hours later, I had written one”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also possible to have &lt;em&gt;mixed episodes&lt;/em&gt;, where one is both manic and depressed &lt;em&gt;at the same time&lt;/em&gt;. For me these would present as irritability, and I would be productive but with no sense of accomplishment. I would even joke about these as well, saying that “annoyance driven development is my standard workflow”. In recent years these mixed episodes were extremely common for me. What’s more, being anywhere on the manic access would also come with less sleep, and being irritable &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; tired was not at all an enjoyable state to be in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I was anywhere on the depressive axis (including during mixed episodes) I would regularly isolate myself. I spent a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of time absent from conferences and events because of this. The isolation wasn’t pleasant, but I would feel &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; socially inept during my episodes that it felt necessary. My depression and irritability would make me feel like I had very little chance of navigating any meaningful human contact without screwing things up. It’s been a barrier to forming closer friends. It’s been a source of strife in my relationships. Isolation is almost certainly not the best coping strategy, but it was still my go-to when my brain was not being kind to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve grown older, my number of hypomanic episodes have reduced, and my mixed and depressive episodes have increased. Bipolar was almost a minor superpower in my 20s, allowing me to be incredibly productive and outgoing. It doesn’t feel like a superpower now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you asked me last year about what sort of mood disorder I might have, I would have absolutely replied some sort of depression, because the manic and mixed episodes didn’t feel like part of a mood disorder, they just felt like me being productive. A huge number of people with bipolar get misdiagnosed with depression for exactly this reason, and the wrong treatment comes with the risk of entering a full manic state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was only reading up on the diagnostic criteria—and &lt;em&gt;especially&lt;/em&gt; about mixed episodes—that I realised how much of this seemed familiar. It was also essential that I got a new doctor, as my old doctor was great with physical health, but not with mental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;treatment&quot;&gt;Treatment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my fears in getting treatment was that the manic episodes are &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; productive and &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; enjoyable that I had fear they would go away. I’m relieved to say that my treatment has been an entirely positive experience and I am amazed at how effective it has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before treatment I was used to having multiple competing trains of thought running through my head at any one time. I’d be thinking about whatever I was doing at the time, but I’d &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; be thinking about whatever project I was working on, and I would &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; be wondering how do birds work, and I would &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; be remembering not to forget that thing I need to do later. This made me good at juggling lots of tasks, but not necessarily that good at focusing on individual ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those familiar with computers, it felt like I had multiple threads running on a single-core CPU. They’d all compete to be running in my consciousness, and I’d context switch between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mood stabilisers &lt;em&gt;reduce my thread-count&lt;/em&gt;. Rather than having multiple competing trains of thought, I instead have mostly one single stream of consciousness. That makes me less good at multi-tasking, but it means my head feels &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; less busy, and my anxiety levels are much, much lower, as I’m not worrying about multiple things at the same time. The tension in my back is gone, I’m sleeping a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; better, and for much of the time I’m better able to focus. I still feel very much like me; indeed, I feel a lot &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; like me with the mood stabilisers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My anti-depressants have filled in my despair-pits, which means I can still feel sad, but I don’t fall into full-blown despair. I’ve had to do a lot of adjusting to that, because there’s a whole range of uncomfortable emotions I wasn’t feeling previously, because I’d hit despair before I reached them. There was a short period where it felt like the blunted my emotional response, but it feels like now I’ve adjusted to them my emotions are at a much more normal and sustainable level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most unexpected results of my treatment is that my sense of smell has improved, and consequently food is tasting better than before. Some of you will know that one of my experiences with depression was that even great food would taste bland, and I’m glad to say that seems to be lifting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The side-effects of my medication have been almost non-existent; sometimes I feel a touch of nasal congestion, and sometimes I need to visit the bathroom more often, but neither of these have any significant impact on my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that not everyone has as good an experience with medication as I do, and so I feel incredibly fortunate that my treatment is so effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-now&quot;&gt;What now?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past it was very common for me to be either extremely “on”, or completely absent. With medication I’m a lot more mellow, so I’m hoping that I can find some kind of a routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve done a lot of shitty things during my depressive and mixed episodes. One of the reasons I isolated myself so frequently is that it felt that I couldn’t trust myself, because I kept hurting others or myself when I absolutely didn’t want to, and isolation was one of the only ways how I knew how to deal with that. I’ve got a lot to work through here, and while I’ve finally found a therapist I feel comfortable with, I imagine it’s going to be something I’m dealing with for quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point I’ll feel more comfortable talking about the specifics of my medication, but not yet. I’m dealing with a lot right now, and even though it feels like the right time to talk about my mental health, I don’t want to get too far into it at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/depression/2018/06/09/bipolar.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/depression/2018/06/09/bipolar.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>A Dystopian Future From Climate Change</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a free dystopian setting for you to use in your next near-future sci-fi! If you want to have a pleasant day, or not think about climate change, then you may wish to skip this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rampant climate change has increased global temperatures to the point where phytoplankton—responsible for two thirds of the Earth’s oxygen production—are experiencing mass die-offs¹. Combined with a collapsed food chain² causing mass extinctions and additional oxygen load from decomposition, both food and oxygen security have become critical, worldwide issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the global rich, oxygen masks and re-breathers are not only ubiquitous, but have become fashion items, with integration into your phone and other parts of your personal area network. With atmospheric oxygen at 15% and falling, the poor are able to survive, but have experience massive cognitive and physical diseases from long-term oxygen starvation. Poor people are no longer able to reproduce, because low blood-oxygen is unable to support a growing fetus; not that that the poor have the energy to have sex in the first place. Sex and exercise are now luxuries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those lucky enough to have work, an oxygenated office is the new equivalent of a health-care plan in the United States. Coffee shops and other retail outlets post “atmospheric oxygen is for customers only” signs. Those who are worst affected by the changes are least able to protest against them, as oxygen deprivation leaves them physically and cognitively incapable of rallying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kicker in this dystopian future is the oxygen produced for consumption by the rich is still powered by fossil fuels. There is a perverse incentive for this to continue, as lowering global oxygen levels mean a greater percentage of people’s budgets are spent on breathing gasses, in which the energy companies hold the means of production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes this such a great setting for a dystopian sci-fi novel is that it’s both plausible, and potentially sooner than most people think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¹ Oxygen security becomes a major issue at about 6°C, or about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2015/12/151201094120.htm&quot;&gt;one hundred years time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;² Global collapse of the food-chain becomes a serious risk at 3.5°C, which &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flassbeck-economics.com/how-climate-change-is-rapidly-taking-the-planet-apart/&quot;&gt;may be as soon as twenty years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/ethics/2016/07/26/dystopian-oxygen-security.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/ethics/2016/07/26/dystopian-oxygen-security.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Visit OSCON Contribute 2016</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s with great delight that myself and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nayafia&quot; class=&quot;social-link&quot;&gt;@nayafia&lt;/a&gt; are hosting Contribute at OSCON this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by some of the amazing hacker lounges held at other conferences, we’re an open space
that’s dedicated to the advancement of Free and Open Source software and related communities.
While we have scheduled sessions for specific projects, we we’re a space for any and all
projects that need a space for coding, community, planning, meetings, or just plain getting together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have dedicated hosts so if you have questions about making your first contributions, want
to share skills, or just need someone to bring you coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about contribute on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/open-source-us/public/schedule/detail/51586&quot;&gt;official OSCON schedule page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2016/05/18/oscon-contribute.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2016/05/18/oscon-contribute.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>An honest conversation about my mental health</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, time for another honest conversation about my mental health. For those of you new to my feed, this is something I do from time to time. Partly because it helps me, and partly because it helps de-stigmatise discussions about mental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be long, rambly, and personal. Imagine you’re on livejournal. There’ll probably be typos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last three weeks I’ve been using a new mood-tracking app (iMood Journal), and I’ve been pretty happy with it compared to what I’ve tried in the past. I have it randomly sampling my mood throughout the day, and it means I can check my subjective experiences versus my recorded evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be reasonable to describe my long-term mental health right now as “adequate”. It’s not great, but it’s not terrible either. You’d probably not come to this assessment if you’ve interacted with me at all, because of the dual factors that socialising makes me feel better, and I will find excuses not to socialise when I’m not doing great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been spending a lot of time looking at what I’ve been doing well and poorly, so lets discuss individual factors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that I can report all manner of achievements and appointments, my natural motivation is pretty much non-existent right now. Almost everything I’m doing is achieved either through fear (public speaking is &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; for fear), or cognitive willpower. Both natural excitement (I’m really enjoying X) and Annoyance Driven Development (I’m going to fix X) are presently absent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being motivationally challenged isn’t much fun. It’s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; easy to fall down with basic human maintenance, like maintaining a tidy work/home environment, sleep, nutrition, and exercise. I’m aware of these risks, and so I’m trying to correct for them, but doing all that using willpower and fear can be exhausting in itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;socialisation&quot;&gt;Socialisation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most difficult thing to talk about, and also the most relevant to my mental health. I’m an extrovert, and it’s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; apparent that I perform extremely poorly without socialising. But there’s a bunch of challenges for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-know-an-intimidating-number-of-people&quot;&gt;I know an intimidating number of people.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little while ago some of you may remember me posting about Sharknado 3. I realised there’d be no way I could squeeze everyone who expressed interest into my home, nor would they likely form a cohesive social group, so instead I thought I’d be clever and arrange to watch bad movies with everyone who responded and their existing friend circles. That tab is &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; sitting open in my browser because the idea of scheduling that many folks into my life is intimidating, and so I’ve scheduled none at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. This is silly. It’s even sillier when I say “I should schedule time with X”, and then worry that I should also be scheduling time with everyone else, and then schedule time with no-one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know from years of playing “The Sims 2” that the solution to this is to throw parties, but those are intimidating because I wonder where I’d host them, how I’d make sure everyone would have a good time, and how I’d get a chance to have meaningful conversations with everyone in the limited period of time. Plus there’s motivation (see above). Mostly I rely upon other people scheduling parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-lack-in-consistent-recurrent-socialisations&quot;&gt;I lack in consistent, recurrent socialisations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people have folks they see regularly at work. They have partners, or family, or other individuals who they interact with on a regular basis. A lot of these interactions happen by default, they don’t need to be planned, they’re just part of everyday living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have these right now. I’ve been doing well with socialising in general, but—with the exception of housemates—it’s rare for me to have seen anyone more than twice before hopping on a flight to somewhere else in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to fix this. Because I travel so much, whenever I’m in a town I try to catch up with as many people as I can, which limits how often I see each individual one. Much more insidiously, part of me doesn’t want to try because no matter how much I want recurrent and consistent interactions, travelling will throw a spanner in the works after a few weeks regardless. There’s also a completely illogical fear of taking up too much of people’s times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;loneliness&quot;&gt;Loneliness&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When other folks aren’t around, and sometimes even when they are, it’s easy for me to feel lonely. There are lots of factors involved with this, and while I’m pleased to say that I’m managing this &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better than I have in the past, it’s still something which I need to be mindful of. Feelings of loneliness will consistently make me socially averse, but because I know what that feels like and how it develops, I’m much better at nipping it in the bud rather than turning into a hermit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;travel-fixing-everything-while-making-it-worse&quot;&gt;Travel: fixing everything while making it worse&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I honestly don’t know how to feel about travel right now. When it’s properly planned, it’s amazing. When I visited New York I got to see almost half my friends there, because I know an intimidating-yet-manageable amount of folks in the New York area. Conferences are great for meeting new people (which I love) and seeing my conference friends, who sometimes feel like the closest thing I have to consistent, recurrent socialising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel is also very easy for me, and really hard to refuse. If I’m invited to speak (with expenses paid) in London, or New York, or Austin, or Tokyo, then of course I’m going to want to say yes. And very often these result in amazing opportunities; they give me audiences and contacts. When I’m trying to change the world, travel is an amazing force multiplier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not travelling can also be problematic. If I feel I’m in a place for a long time, I can stop functioning properly altogether. Rather than having consistent, recurrent socialisations, I instead just don’t see my friends at all, partially due to the mistaken belief that I have plenty of time to catch up with them. Plus not travelling causes decay to my ties everywhere else in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel also means that no matter where I am in the world, I’m also missing someplace else. Plus distances and timezones wreck havoc with any sort of ties with other humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stories-and-role-models&quot;&gt;Stories and role-models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know a lot of people who have the same or even a similar lifestyle to what I have, and this makes things just a little more tricky when wondering “so what do I do now?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m motivationally challenged, but great at hiding it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My ongoing happiness level over the last month has been “adequate”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I travel a lot, which makes socialising hard.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I lack good stories and role-models for this sort of thing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s no real take-away from all this, but it’s good for me to talk about it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve read all the way to the end? You’re amazing! &amp;lt;3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/depression/2016/04/12/honest-conversation-about-mental-health.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/depression/2016/04/12/honest-conversation-about-mental-health.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>National Rick Astley Hotline Upgraded</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Some of you know I run the Australian National Rick Astley Hotline, on +61-3-8652-1453 . Today, in celebration of troublemakers everywhere, I’ve upgraded it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calling the number will &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; give you the classic Rick you’ve always loved, but &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; you can use your keypad for extra joy. I’ll let you discover all the options, and how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In celebration of the upgrade, I’ve &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; provisioned the United States National Rick Astley Hotline, on +1-760-706-RICK (+1-760-706-7425).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to help defray my costs, you can do so &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/_pjf&quot;&gt;via Patreon&lt;/a&gt;, but mostly I want you to share the numbers with your friends. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re welcome, internet, you’re welcome. :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2016/04/01/rick-astley-hotline-upgraded.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2016/04/01/rick-astley-hotline-upgraded.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Cure Evangelism</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Okay Internet, we need to talk about cure evangelism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you’ll have friends who aren’t doing too well. It could be their mental health. It could be their physical health. Maybe it’s social anxiety, or depression, or fatigue, or something else. Whatever it is, they’ve posted about it to social media as a way of getting support and maybe feeling a bit better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, there are correct and incorrect ways to respond to this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless they’ve specifically requested advice, the correct ways include sending love, saying you hope they feel better soon, or offering to help if they need it. Incorrect ways include telling them that they should try yoga to fix their social anxiety, dancing to fix their depression, or bathing in coconut oil to fix their computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These things &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; have worked for you, but no matter how good your intentions are, the person you’re trying to help feel better probably doesn’t &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; advice, they want support and love instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s worse, if they’ve mentioned their condition to anyone at all, they probably keep getting the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; advice. The advice you’ve given them is likely something they’ve already tried, or—more likely—you’ve asked them to do something which their condition &lt;em&gt;prevents&lt;/em&gt; them from doing. This sort of advice isn’t just frustrating, it’s &lt;em&gt;exhausting&lt;/em&gt;, and it makes people less likely to turn to social media for support in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So please, care about your friends, look after them, but don’t cure evangelise.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2016/03/21/cure-evangelism.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2016/03/21/cure-evangelism.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Changing The World Is Done In Small Steps</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s 4am, and I’ve been goth-clubbing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kittylyst&quot; class=&quot;social-link&quot;&gt;@kittylyst&lt;/a&gt;, which of course meant I ended up having discussions about technologies with three-letter acronyms, and how to change the world. I have strong opinions about this, so I’m sharing them with you all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of people seem to think that very few people can change the world, but I feel that’s patently false. You change the world merely by living in it. That may be supporting the status quo (which is easy), or by rallying against it (which is more difficult). But for anyone who’s fought against how things are, it can feel like progress is impossible. It can feel that no matter how hard you try, you don’t make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s bollocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your brain is wired to appreciate &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt; rewards. Things which happen today, or tomorrow. But societal and global change happen slowly; they take years, or decades, or &lt;em&gt;generations&lt;/em&gt;. You can watch it happening, too. Between 1980 and 2010, the number of people living in extreme poverty went from 40% of the world’s population to 14%. In 2000 no country in the world had marriage equality laws; now we have twenty-two countries with same-sex marriage laws. Heck, we’re even making significant inroads on Malaria, which results in some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.givingwhatwecan.org/post/2015/12/bednets-have-prevented-450-million-cases-of-malaria/&quot; title=&quot;Bednets have prevented 450 million cases of malaria&quot;&gt;most satisfying animated maps I’ve ever seen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But none of these things have happened &lt;em&gt;quickly&lt;/em&gt;. They’ve taken decades, and often have decades more of progress behind them which you don’t see. While we very much &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; the world to change overnight, it’s very rare that this happens. Progress is hard work, and in some cases it’s frustrating and &lt;em&gt;unsatisfying&lt;/em&gt;, but it’s so absolutely and definitely possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what you should be working towards. Not thinking about how do I change the world tomorrow, or next week, but &lt;em&gt;how do I change the rest of human existence&lt;/em&gt;. That may be amplifying the voices of others. It may be improving the lives of people you’ve never met. It may be discussing ideas which may be uncomfortable but necessary. It may be producing media to be watched by kids so that &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; children are raised in a much better society than we have today. It may be doing all of the above, and much, much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good investors know how to take a long-term view, and changing the world for the better is &lt;em&gt;very much&lt;/em&gt; an investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So please, don’t give up hope, don’t think your efforts aren’t making a difference. Play the long game, be willing to fight for an end-game you may never see during your natural lifetime, and don’t fall into the trap of thinking that you’re powerless. Because you’re not, but &lt;em&gt;thinking&lt;/em&gt; you are can cause you to shy away from doing all the good that you’re genuinely capable of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/ethics/2016/02/14/changing-the-world-is-done-in-small-steps.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/ethics/2016/02/14/changing-the-world-is-done-in-small-steps.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Win my hat at linux.conf.au 2016</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For almost a decade, I’ve been presenting conference talks wearing a black top-hat.
Indeed, this has become one of the most recognisable parts of my stage-persona. So I’m
very pleased to say that you can win my original conference hat as part of the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://linux.conf.au/&quot;&gt;linux.conf.au&lt;/a&gt; charity raffle, raising money for &lt;a href=&quot;https://givewhereyoulive.com.au/&quot;&gt;Give Where You Live&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;right smaller&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;fancybox&quot; rel=&quot;group&quot; href=&quot;/images/tech/hat-raffle.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tech/hat-raffle.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photography by Erin Walsh&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hat comes with a beautiful note of authenticity—written by me—certifying
that it is indeed my conference hat. The hat-band, flower, and pins on my hat
all have great sentimental value to me, and are not incldued as part of the
raffle, but if you’ve attended the bioinformatics miniconfs you can probably
recover my genetic material. You should be aware the the hat has seen almost a
decade of regular use, and so also has significant signs of wear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those wondering, I’m not giving up the wearing of hats at conferences; instead
I’m replacing my hat substrate, and I’m delighted that the hat that I’ve
worn at so many &lt;a href=&quot;https://linux.conf.au/&quot;&gt;linux.conf.au&lt;/a&gt; events can be donated back to the community.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2016/02/02/win-my-hat-at-lca2016.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2016/02/02/win-my-hat-at-lca2016.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Fact Check: Will Pap Smears Still Be Covered by Medicare?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s fact checking time! Today, the claim that pap smears will no longer be free in Australia!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That claim is false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t link to the article in question here, because it’s misleading clickbait, but the claim that pap smears and other pathology services will no longer be covered by Medicare is scaremongering, or at least a pretty big stretch from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change which is happening is that pathology providers will no longer be given an &lt;em&gt;additional&lt;/em&gt; payment for bulk-billed tests. The cost of the procedure itself is still covered by Medicare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article is &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; misleading when it claims that “Medicare rebates for pathology and diagnostic imaging services haven’t increased for over a decade, and now they are being cut”. The incentive payment which is being cut was introduced in 2009-2010 (much less than ten years ago) to encourage providers to bulk-bill, and was a payment to providers &lt;em&gt;in addition&lt;/em&gt; to that provided by Medicare. However since its introduction there’s been only a small increase in bulk-billing (1-3%), but a relatively large cost in incentive payments (about $1.3b over five years). It’s this additional payment that is being cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The incentive payments which are being cut range from $1.60–$4.00 per test, although additional incentives for are provided for children, concession card holders, and services in certain regional areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response it’s conceivable that some pathology providers may choose not to no longer bulk-bill for pap smears, and if those providers charge more than the Medicare rebate then patients will see out-of-pocket costs; a situation which we already see with some GPs and specialists. However we still expect to see plenty of practices continuing to bulk-bill, because bulk-billing is extremely popular with patients and guarantees a larger customer base. I would speculate that bulk-billed pap smears will still be easy to obtain, as in 2014-15 a whopping 98.7% of out-of-hospital pathology services were at no cost to the patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For detailed, primary information about the changes, you can read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aph.gov.au/About_Parliament/Parliamentary_Departments/Parliamentary_Library/FlagPost/2015/December/Changes_to_bulk_billing_incentives&quot;&gt;Australian Parliament post on the subject&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much thanks goes to Kat McGee and Daniel Reeders who did the original research, and Linda Kirkman for bringing it to my attention. I’ve just double-checked the facts, made a graphic on Facebook, and put them into my own words.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2016/01/06/will-pap-smears-no-longer-be-free.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2016/01/06/will-pap-smears-no-longer-be-free.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                     
	</channel>
</rss>
