<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>paul.j.fenwick</title>
		<description>Freedom Loving Scientist</description>
		<link>http://pjf.id.au</link>
		<atom:link href="http://pjf.id.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Reality distortion field</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I’m accused of having a “reality distortion field”, which warps the universe in such a way that it makes my life better. Today’s arrival at the airport was an amazing example of that in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m flying back to Australia today on a reasonably late flight; at least, I thought that I was. Upon arriving at the airport, and presenting myself for check-in, I was informed that my flight was tomorrow. I had arrived a day early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt a little foolish, but overall my reaction to this discovery was amusement. I’d been jetsetting about so much, and really having such a great time at KiwiFoo and my friends, that I hadn’t actually noticed the off-by-one error when it came to my flight date. In the worst case scenario I head back into Auckland,do some exploring, and find myself a cheap hostel or backpackers to stay in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But since I was already at the airport, and I’m very much looking forward to getting back home, I thought I’d ask to see if I could be transferred to today’s flight. If it ends up being too expensive for my tastes then I can always decline, and asking is a relatively quick task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I headed over to the ticketing desk. There was one man, with &lt;em&gt;three&lt;/em&gt; phones and a radio, clearly having a bad time. The phones wouldn’t stop ringing, the radio needed constant attention, and he seemed to be terribly overworked. As I was to discover, he was effectively doing the job of two people today. He looked stressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is where I reveal to you how the reality distortion field works. You be extremely nice to people; if you can, you try to make their day awesome. I made it very clear with my body language and my smile that I was totally fine waiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the phones stopped ringing for a few minutes, I noted that he looked very popular (which actually elicited a smile), and that I really didn’t want to bother him. He thanked me for my patience, asked how he could help, and then apologised when the phone rang again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later, again between calls, I explained my situation. He consoled in me about how his day was going, and explained how all the phones worked, and what sort of emergencies they represented. Holy smokes this guy was keeping a lot of things running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While was was on TWO phones and a radio (one in the hand, one on the desk, and one under the shoulder) he indicated with his remaining hand that he’d like to see my travel documents. Because this is a guy who multitasks like a boss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the phones quietened again, he smiled at me and said: “Hey, thanks for being so patient. Today’s been pretty busy. I’ve moved you onto tonight’s flight, and put you in an exit row so you’ve got extra legroom. Does that work for you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explain that it most definitely does, and I ask if there’s a transfer fee or anything that I’d have to pay. I’ve got an economy ticket, and I know that normally to change flights is going to be rather pricey. But I ask this mainly as a formality, it’s pretty clear by this stage that reality had been distorted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh no, you’ve been so patient I can’t charge you for that. You have a nice day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I comment that he’s just &lt;em&gt;made&lt;/em&gt; my day, and he comments that this is the second time he’s heard that today. I grin, and tell him that this must be because he’s making the world a better place. He directs me over to &lt;em&gt;priority&lt;/em&gt; check-in (even though I don’t qualify on this flight), and I thank him again while all the phones start to ring once more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story continues with priority check-in making sure that I’ve got pre-clearance for immigration and customs (because they can), and making sure I’m actually happy with my seat because it has limited recline capabilities. I assure them that really, it’s fine (I don’t like reclining my seat because it feels rude to whoever’s behind me), and wish everyone a fantastic day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the reason everyone was so lovely to me is because I was so lovely to them. Of course, the irony is that being lovely to others comes most easily when I’ve been having a great day myself. The reality distortion field is most likely to take a great day and make it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But either way, I’m still pretty happy. I’ve got a flight a day early, I’ve got a quick route through customs, and after I post this entry, I have my first opportunity in a fortnight to seriously right down and hack some code. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/04/14/reality-distortion-field.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/04/14/reality-distortion-field.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>On gendered toilets at conferences</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this, it may be because I suggested that the world would be a better place if we saw fewer gendered toilets at your conference. I’d like to explain why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, we’ve lived in a world where we put people in boxes, and the most common of those boxes is a thing called “gender”. The traditional thinking has been that there are two genders, and &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; fits into one or the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the traditional thinking is pretty darn awful; it makes the world significantly more uncomfortable for anyone who doesn’t fit clearly fall into our ideas of binary gender. That can include anyone born with genitals that don’t match the traditional thinking, anyone who isn’t happy with the gender they were assigned at birth, anyone who doesn’t fit our gender stereotypes, anyone who doesn’t want a gender, anyone who’s gender is fluid or ambiguous… It includes an awful lot of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living in a world that enforces a gender binary is uncomfortable if you don’t fit neatly into it, and gendered toilets go a long way to contributing to that. If you’re currently transitioning, which facilities do you use? How will other people react to that choice? Will you even be safe? That’s something a lot of people never have to worry about, but if you’re trans, fluid, agendered, or queer, then it’s something you might have to worry about. Every. Single. Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it sucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gendered toilets are a form of discrimination against anyone who doesn’t fit the traditional views of gender. Often they exist not because any harm is intended, but just because there was no thought of arranging things any other way. I dearly hope that your conference is a place where people can feel comfortable being themselves, where they can exchange ideas, where they can be creative, where they can do great things and make the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By all means, indicate if sanitary disposal facilities are available; but please help your conference be a place where we can celebrate diversity of gender, rather than a place which unconsciously suppresses it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/04/14/gendered-toilets-at-conferences.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/04/14/gendered-toilets-at-conferences.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Tanya and Danjite are awesome</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’m in Auckland after KiwiFoo, which was pretty darn awesome, and well worth a hectic travel schedule to attend. And while I have a lot of good things to say about my contributions at the conference, I instead want publicly say a few words of thanks to two people who have consistently made made my life better, and whom I deeply appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class='social-link' href='https://twitter.com/tanya'&gt;Tanya Gray&lt;/a&gt; I had the pleasure of meeting at Codemania last year, and has consistently blown me away with her generosity and desire to help others. She’s dedicated to teaching programming and technology at schools, and is doing an amazing job of encouraging diversity and participation. But for me personally, Tanya consistently and proactively steps forward to make sure I’m okay any time I might possibly be near Auckland. I have Tanya to thank for adventures through awesome underground rivers, for a place to stay, for helping me get around, and even for smoothly run conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday, Tanya drove all the way from KiwiFoo back to Auckland, picked me up at midnight, and drove all the way back again to arrive around 1:30am. She furnished me with one of her own sleeping bags. She’d already staked out a sleeping area for me a Foo. In other words, Tanya enabled me to have the best time possible this weekend, and I am deeply, deeply thankful to her, not only for this, but for all the good she is doing in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class='social-link' href='https://twitter.com/danjite'&gt;Daniel Spector&lt;/a&gt;, whom I met many years ago at a Linux conference, has been an absolute rock, even when we’ve been separated by great distances. Daniel has checked if I’ve been okay when I’ve been feeling down. He’s encouraged me to chase my dreams when I’ve been feeling up. He’s had endless patience when I’ve needed advice, and endless generosity and hospitality whenever I’ve been anywhere nearby. Daniel believes in me even when I don’t believe in myself, and that has made an enormous difference to my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel has been responsible for amazing adventures, for providing me with food and shelter, for fascinating conversations, excellent referrals, meeting amazing people, and some truly, truly awful puns. I adore him to bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/04/13/tanya-and-danjite-are-awesome.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/04/13/tanya-and-danjite-are-awesome.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Why diversity in tech is so hard to achieve</title>
				<description>&lt;figure class='right'&gt;&lt;a class='fancybox' href='/images/tech/anna-facebook-post.png' rel='group'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/tech/anna-facebook-post.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This was originally made as a response to a &lt;a href='https://www.facebook.com/paul.fenwick/posts/10152061360984611'&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt; discussing diversity issues in tech.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anna: I am a feminist who has attended and spoken at your events. I’m not familiar with the experiences which you’ve had in the past; I’ve not been involved with them, and so I am in no position to comment. I have absolutely no desire to ruin your reputation or spread rumours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However I am perfectly happy to comment on things that I’ve personally observed, and to call you out when I feel that you’re being actively harmful to diversity, especially diversity in open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the 7th March (give or take a timezone) you publicly posted¹ about a conference that catered specifically to a group that is under-represented in both IT and FOSS. Since I gave the OSCON 2013 closing keynote on the processes by which marginalised groups in tech remain marginalised (even when there’s absolutely no hostility or ill intent) I’d normally be delighted with any post that promotes diversity and outreach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, that’s not what your post was about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, it was a post that belittled an already minority group. I’m not really fond of belittling anyone, but I’m especially not fond of it when it comes from a person in a position of power, such as a conference organiser. It’s even worse when &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; conference organiser joins in, which is exactly what happened here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not a member of that minority group going to ConFoo, but if I was, then after seeing your post I would be thinking twice. Given the public behaviour I’d seen of the conference organisers, I wouldn’t feel comfortable discussing my non-mainstream sexuality. I certainly wouldn’t feel comfortable discussing any work I’d done in promoting diversity. If I was working on technology that helped with issues specific to the minority in which I belonged, I’d be concerned that this too would somehow be belittled… and none of this has anything to do with any &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; hostility at the conference; all that’s needed is the perception that hostility will arise for someone to be silenced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s one of the biggest reasons why diversity is so hard to achieve. Speaking at a conference &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be about the tech. It &lt;em&gt;shouldn’t&lt;/em&gt; be about worrying if you’re going to be harassed, belittled, shunned, stared at, made fun of, or worse. Outreach is not playing favourites; outreach is simply saying: “Hey, there are others like you. That lack of diversity you see isn’t because the people here suck, that’s just a historical artefact.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outreach programmes are a &lt;em&gt;compliment&lt;/em&gt; to the communities from which they grow. If there’s an outreach programme for a certain technology, then enough of a minority group in that technology think that it’s worthwhile to introduces others to it. Toxic communities rarely result in outreach; their members just leave instead. But healthy, active communities result in healthy, active outreach programmes. That’s something that should be celebrated, not something that should be the butt of a joke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anna, I know that you want it to just be about the tech³. I want exactly the same thing. I’m not going to ask you to go promoting outreach programmes, but if you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; want tech conferences to be about the tech, then I am going to ask you to stop making fun of the people and communities who are running those programmes. By all means, criticise conferences on their technical merits; but please don’t criticise a conference just because of the gender or sexuality of the people who attend them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¹ A screenshot of the public post is attached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;² My material was drawn from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gretachristina.typepad.com/greta_christinas_weblog/2009/09/race-sex-atheism.html&quot;&gt;excellent explanations by Greta Christina&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;³ Blog post: &lt;a href=&quot;http://afilina.com/it-is-not-about-gender/&quot;&gt;It is not about gender.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/03/21/why-diversity-is-hard-to-achieve.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/03/21/why-diversity-is-hard-to-achieve.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Exobrain setup is now even easier!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Exobrain is my collection of digital minions which help me run my life. They know my goals, my location, my to-do list, and help me best plan what I’m doing, both personally and professionally. Best of all, none of my data is revealed to third parties, because I control all my agents, and all the code is open source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve previously written about how to &lt;a href=&quot;/tech/2014/02/09/automate-your-life-with-exobrain.html&quot;&gt;automate your life with exobrain&lt;/a&gt;. Today, I’m going to talk more about how to get started with an exobrain install. I want to thank everyone who attended my talk at &lt;a href=&quot;http://confoo.ca/&quot; title=&quot;ConFoo conference&quot;&gt;Confoo.ca&lt;/a&gt; for their feedback and suggestions, and especially everyone who attended the install-fest on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve previously tried to get Exobrain installed, you would have known it had a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of dependencies. I’m very glad to say that we’re moving towards a system where instead of getting &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; with Exobrain, you now only get the parts you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than one huge distribution, we now have the Exobrain &lt;em&gt;core&lt;/em&gt;, which contains the framework and supporting infrastructure, and &lt;em&gt;components&lt;/em&gt;, which allow you to hook into individual services. Installing the core still requires you to walk through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjf/exobrain/#installation&quot;&gt;Exobrain install guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individual components now only require a couple of commands to get up and running. For example, you may install &lt;code&gt;Exobrain::Twitter&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Exobrain::Beeminder&lt;/code&gt; to communicate with Twitter or &lt;a href=&quot;https://beeminder.com&quot; title=&quot;Quantify your goals with Beeminder&quot;&gt;Beeminder&lt;/a&gt; respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Components come with their own configuration code, which means there’s no more digging through &lt;code&gt;.exobrainrc&lt;/code&gt; files. Here’s how you’d get started with Beeminder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cpanm Exobrain::Beeminder
$ exobrain setup Beeminder&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will launch an interactive process that will walk you through obtaining an API key, and will even test to make sure it’s working. Once complete, the Beeminder services show up as their own service group:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ubic status

exobrain.beeminder
    exobrain.beeminder.source       running (pid 30359)
    exobrain.beeminder.notify       running (pid 30378)
    exobrain.beeminder.sink         running (pid 30389)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we can see that the Beeminder component comes with three parts. For any component, the “source” reads from that data source and emits measurement packets onto the Exobrain bus. The “sink” reads intents from the bus, and transmits them to the external service. In the case of the Beeminder component, it also comes with a “notify” agent, which generates notifications whenever a Beeminder data-point is updated (provided we have Beeminder call-backs configured correctly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because each component is in their own status group, you can enable or disable them easily with &lt;code&gt;ubic start exobrain.beeminder&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;ubic stop exobrain.beeminder&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the hood, components provide a much cleaner way of writing agents, with many components supplying roles which allow automatically handle connection and configuration to services. They also open the door to writing your own private components which can be updated inpdependently to the rest of Exobrain, or which you can distribute to others!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/03/06/exobrain-setup-is-now-even-easier.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/03/06/exobrain-setup-is-now-even-easier.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>The iOS SSL/TLS bug is worse than you think</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Holy smokes. So having looked at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imperialviolet.org/2014/02/22/applebug.html&quot;&gt;actual code&lt;/a&gt; for this, the bug in iOS / OSX is &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; worse than described &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/why-apples-huge-security-flaw-is-so-scary-1529041062&quot;&gt;on gizmodo&lt;/a&gt;. The article is misleading when it says your home network is safe, it’s &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;. If I poison your DNS queries, compromise your home router (they’re &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; exploitable), have privileged access to the network infrastructure between you and what you’re connecting to, or all manner of other things, then I &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; your connection, and whatever data you send across it; credit card details, bank account logins, facebook passwords, all of it. If I hijack anything that’s doing a software update, then I may potentially own your device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, if you’re already logged into a website, I may even be able to steal your cookies and act as you without you even needing to enter a username and password at all. Seriously, this exploit really is about as bad as it gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two-factor auth will mitigate some, but not &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of the damage here. The only way to close this hole is to upgrade your vulnerable apple devices now. Please do this. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; What am I saying? Two factor auth isn’t going to help you one damn bit. If you’ve just typed in your account number and password to your bank, &lt;em&gt;of course&lt;/em&gt; you’re going to supply me with your one-time password as well, &lt;em&gt;because you think it’s your bank asking for it&lt;/em&gt;, and your browser isn’t going to tell you otherwise. You’re going to supply it even if the bank texts it to your phone; in fact, that just makes the whole thing feel &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; legitimate. So please, really, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; upgrade. Right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/why-apples-huge-security-flaw-is-so-scary-1529041062&quot;&gt;Gizmodo article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imperialviolet.org/2014/02/22/applebug.html&quot;&gt;Code with discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CVE-2014-1266&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/02/25/the-ios-bug-is-worse-than-you-think.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/02/25/the-ios-bug-is-worse-than-you-think.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>How I Claimed $270 of Beeminder Bounties</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday I paid &lt;a href=&quot;https://beeminder.com&quot; title=&quot;Quantify your goals with Beeminder&quot;&gt;Beeminder&lt;/a&gt; $5 because I didn’t floss my teeth when I promised that I would. That evening, &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; was the one collecting $270 from Beeminder…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you’re not familiar with me, I’m outstandingly lazy. I really dislike &lt;em&gt;having&lt;/em&gt; to do anything at all. I’m totally fine with &lt;em&gt;choosing&lt;/em&gt; to do things, but I push back pretty hard against the universe when something &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be done. This is why I’m so big on automation, it reduces the things to have to be done by me, and allows me to practice &lt;em&gt;efficient laziness&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are some things one simply can’t automate; flossing your teeth, running a business, doing one’s taxes, getting some exercise. While I might be able to write digital agents that can &lt;em&gt;assist&lt;/em&gt; me with those tasks, fundamentally they’re things that I have to do. The problem is, left to my own devices, I rarely will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is one time when I’ll take action, and that’s when presented with the threat of imminent failure. If you’ve read WBW’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://waitbutwhy.com/2013/10/why-procrastinators-procrastinate.html&quot;&gt;excellent article on procrastination&lt;/a&gt; then you’ll understand that the panic monster is one of the few things that will get chronic procrastinators to actually move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For tasks with big, looming deadlines such as &lt;a href=&quot;/talks&quot;&gt;my talks&lt;/a&gt;, there’s a very clear, and visceral threat of failure. They’re even worse than most deadlines, because they’re &lt;em&gt;public speaking&lt;/em&gt;, which is already flat out terrifying, and most of my talks are given in Australia, where everything is trying to kill you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, if I need to get something done, I’ll promise to present a talk on it, safe in the knowledge that the fear of public ridicule and the thought of my audience &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saltwater_Crocodile&quot;&gt;taking&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stone_fish&quot;&gt;me&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_White_Shark&quot;&gt;to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Box_jellyfish&quot;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_ringed_octopus&quot;&gt;beach&lt;/a&gt; will be enough to terrify me into action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet there’s a problem. Small things which I should be doing regularly, like flossing my teeth, or doing exercise, come with with no dramatic failure cliffs. And let’s face it, planning to live one’s life by only doing the most terrifying things at the last possible moment isn’t exactly the most optimal way to live. This is where Beeminder comes in handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://beeminder.com&quot; title=&quot;Quantify your goals with Beeminder&quot;&gt;Beeminder&lt;/a&gt; provides the ability to establish &lt;em&gt;commitment devices&lt;/em&gt;. In the same way that I’ll promise to give a talk on software I would &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; to write, I can use Beeminder to promise to do something that I would &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; to do, but which I know future me will be unlikely to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beeminder is exceptionally good at taking large or ongoing tasks, and splitting them into smaller, more achievable goals. It then draws the most friggin’ nerdtastic graphs ever, with rolling averages, goal lines, predictive curves, and all sorts of goodies, so you can see just how well you’re doing. The most important of these is the ‘yellow brick road’. If you’re on that, then you’re on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I might achieve my long-term task of good dental hygiene by having a goal to floss three times each week. Or I might turn my goal of writing a 5,000 word essay into the task of writing 250 words per day for 20 days. Beeminder makes it very easy to see if I’m achieving my goal, or if I’m at risk of falling behind. And if I over-perform (maybe by writing 1000 words one day), then Beeminder will cut me some slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However the real power of Beeminder is that you can pledge an amount of money against your goal. Promising that I’m going to floss my teeth thrice weekly may not be very motivating, but knowing that I’ll lose $5 if I don’t make my flossing deadline is enough to have me stumble into the bathroom before bed, rather than promising to myself that I will do it later. And while I can change my goals at any time, I have to do it at least a week in advance, so I can’t weasel out of something just because I don’t want to do it right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I pay out on the occasional pledge, those amounts have been absolutely worth it. Overall I’m paying about $0.20/week for good dental health, and maybe $0.08/day to keep my inbox under control. A Beeminder pledge has also kept me attending my last 30 dance lessons, by giving me just enough of a nudge to not come up with excuses as to why I’m too busy to go, and I’ve not paid a penny to Beeminder for that goal, as I’ve never got behind in my dance lessons when I’ve promised to be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of cool &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.beeminder.com/akrasia/&quot;&gt;cognitive science behind Beeminder&lt;/a&gt;, but one of the neat things is they’re &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; committed to using their own system to ensure that important tasks like user-visible improvements, blog-posts, and general support get done. And by very committed, I mean that the Beeminder team &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.beeminder.com/blogdog/&quot;&gt;will pay out pledges&lt;/a&gt; to users that call them out if they fall behind on one of their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what happened last Tuesday. One of the founders hadn’t spent enough hours on Beeminder that week, and I ended up $270 richer as a result, and that was one of the smaller pledges they have on the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, being me, I don’t want to feel I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to check if any bounties are payable, so I’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjf/exobrain/blob/master/bin/source/beeminder-bounties&quot;&gt;written some code&lt;/a&gt; to check for me. I’ve got no qualms about being efficiently lazy when it comes to motivating others. ;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/02/22/how-i-claimed-270-of-beeminder-bounties.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/02/22/how-i-claimed-270-of-beeminder-bounties.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Is social media making us antisocial?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed a concerning trend over the last few years, and I’m not exactly sure what to do about it. As a culture, our communication habits are changing, and the results may be terrible for our mental health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a long post, and it’s going to help if we start with a brief review of communication over the ages, beginning with face-to-face interactions. These provide plenty of &lt;em&gt;non-verbal&lt;/em&gt; signals, such as body language and vocal tone. It’s often clear when interacting with someone if they’re paying attention or distracted; if they’re angry, joking, happy, or just bored. (Although even face-to-face, we’re still good at &lt;a href=&quot;http://not-a-jerk.blogspot.com/2012/03/fighting-for-no-reasonhow-were-hard.html&quot; title=&quot;Fighting for no reason, how we're hard-hired to be hostile&quot;&gt;getting things wrong&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point we learned how to read and write, and while letters were an important stage in our development, I’m restricting myself to looking at direct and instantaneous communication in this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skip forward a few thousand years to the telephone. This technology was game-changing. It allowed people to talk, even when separated by distance. While it wasn’t possible to read body language over the telephone, one could still read vocal tone. Telephones were a fixture in people’s homes, so you generally knew you had someone’s full attention when you were talking to them, and it became rapidly apparent when you did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the advent of computers, things became more interesting, and definitely more diverse. were find ourselves with IRC, chatrooms, SMS, instant messenger, and a variety of other text-based communication forms. These provided fewer non-verbal signals (emoticons are a notable exception here), along with less clues for when someone was distracted with other things or not. But still, one used these forms of communication to maintain a conversation with an individual, or a directed group of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='pullquote'&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;i class='fa fa-quote-left fa-2x pull-left'&gt; &lt;/i&gt; The dominant mode of communication with social media is 'post-and-hope'.  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now we’re seeing a form of communication which is radically different from what we’ve experienced in the past: social media. The dominant mode of communication with social media is the &lt;em&gt;undirected broadcast&lt;/em&gt;, what I call “post-and-hope”. You post on your wall, or tweet to the world, and people may respond, or they may not. When they do respond, the responses are more ephemeral. It’s harder to have a personal conversation when all six-hundred of your friends are watching it, or you’re limited to 140 characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media doesn’t preclude more directed conversations, but it is shifting the ways in which we’re communicating. Combined with the rapid uptake of mobile electronics, where a friend being ‘online’ may simply mean they’ve opened their phone for a few seconds in an elevator, there’s even more uncertainty associated with directed conversations than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is that for many people, a significant amount of communication is broadcasted, rather than directed, and the continuity of a conversation is more unpredictable, and more likely to evaporate without a clear verbal or textual signal (such as “catch you later”), than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class='right'&gt;&lt;a class='fancybox' href='/images/personal/depression-instant-messaging.png' rel='group'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/personal/depression-instant-messaging.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;For adolescents who perceive themselves to have low friendship quality (the top line), instant messaging is significantly protective to mental health¹.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m aware that “all this technology is making us antisocial” is hardly a new sentiment. My parents expressed concern about me hanging out on bulletin boards with ‘electronic people’ as a teenager, even though I viewed that as exceptionally good for my social and intellectual development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the scientific literature shows that spending time on instant messenger is &lt;em&gt;protective&lt;/em&gt; of mental health if one is feeling socially isolated¹, studies into social media itself seem to be less clear, and I’m still trying to make sense of them. I’ve included references at the bottom of the article, in case you wish to do some reading yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However this is a personal post, and one thing I’m concerned about is the trends in my own social habits. I communicate with many more people than I used to, but I’m much less close to any of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='pullquote'&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;i class='fa fa-quote-left fa-2x pull-left'&gt; &lt;/i&gt; I communicate with many more people, but I'm less close to any of them.  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go back five years ago, and I have a small number of close friends whom I felt very comfortable talking to, and we would share our experiences and thoughts extensively. While we weren’t in constant contact, it was very reassuring to know they existed, and I took for granted that if I was worried or anxious, or wanted to share news of a success or receive guidance on some defeat, that I’d have close friends to fall back on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, things feel different. My close friends are still my friends, but communicate with them less. When I do communicate, the conversations are more shallow. I’ve noticed that’s often &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; fault; I’m less likely to have an on-line conversation as a dedicated activity, and they seem to more often start as side-effects from other social media use, and dry up just as quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class='right'&gt;&lt;a class='fancybox' href='/images/personal/support-and-depression.png' rel='group'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/personal/support-and-depression.png' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Social support is protective against depression²&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That worries me, not just from a social standpoint, but also from a mental health one. We know that having a confidant—someone with whom one feels they can talk to about anything—is hugely protective to one’s mental health. If social media &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; making us less close, then we run the risk of many more people suffering from mental health issues due to that isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure part of the reason for these changes is the sheer number of people with whom I interact with on-line. If you were to go back a decade ago, I had &lt;em&gt;dozens&lt;/em&gt; of people in my instant messenger contact list. Today, my Facebook friends number in the &lt;em&gt;hundreds&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t yet have enough evidence to say that this is becoming an issue for society in general, but I’m concerned that it might be. There’s a number of studies showing links between social media usage and depression, but these don’t show &lt;em&gt;causality&lt;/em&gt;; people feeling isolated may be using social media more as a means of support. That’s certainly something I’ve done in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s just as concerning for me—if not more so—is that that systems like Facebook are increasingly taking the choice of which stories to display on one’s feed out of the user’s control, and are instead selecting what they feel will provide you with the best ‘personalized feed’. That’s generally understood to be whatever causes you to continue to interact with Facebook, since that means you’ll view the most ads. However it opens the possibly of &lt;em&gt;algorithmic isolation&lt;/em&gt;, simply because your important posts may not be shown to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook is particularly notable for burying posts where the author expresses that they’re sad or unhappy. That’s not a deliberate decision on Facebook’s behalf, but nobody ‘likes’ their friend being unhappy, and many people don’t know what to say in the comments. To Facebook, a sad post looks like a boring post, because nobody’s interacting with it. I’ve found that adding “Likes=Hugs” to the top of my writing is sometimes enough to overcome this, but it’s rare that a post about one feeling sad can compete with a picture of a cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it seems that every new form of communication is heralded as being bad for our mental health soon after it’s introduced, and often those fears end up being unfounded. Social media and its associated modes of communication are still very young, and while they’re an active topic of study, it may still be some time until we truly understand their impact on society and individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, you can subscribe to me on Facebook &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/paul.fenwick&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;references_and_further_reading&quot;&gt;References and further reading&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¹ Selfhout, Maarten H.W., Susan J.T. Branje, M. Delsing, Tom F.M. ter Bogt, and Wim H.J. Meeus. ”&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nutrociencia.com.br/upload_files/artigos_download/internet,%20depression.pdf&quot;&gt;Different Types of Internet Use, Depression, and Social Anxiety: The Role of Perceived Friendship Quality.&lt;/a&gt;” Journal of Adolescence 32, no. 4 (August 2009): 819–833. doi:10.1016/j.adolescence.2008.10.011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;² Eaton et al, ”&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/pmhdepression?course_id=971121&quot;&gt;Major Depression in the Population: A Public Health Approach&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreno, Megan A., Lauren A. Jelenchick, Katie G. Egan, Elizabeth Cox, Henry Young, Kerry E. Gannon, and Tara Becker. “&lt;a href=&quot;http://europepmc.org/articles/PMC3110617&quot;&gt;Feeling Bad on Facebook: Depression Disclosures by College Students on a Social Networking Site.&lt;/a&gt;” Depression and Anxiety 28, no. 6 (2011): 447–455.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O’Keeffe, G. S., K. Clarke-Pearson, and Council on Communications and Media. “&lt;a href=&quot;http://machadok.faculty.mjc.edu/SocialMediaImpact.pdf&quot;&gt;The Impact of Social Media on Children, Adolescents, and Families.&lt;/a&gt;” PEDIATRICS 127, no. 4 (March 28, 2011): 800–804. doi:10.1542/peds.2011-0054.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valenzuela, Sebastián, Namsu Park, and Kerk F. Kee. “&lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1083-6101.2009.01474.x/full&quot;&gt;Is There Social Capital in a Social Network Site?: Facebook Use and College Students’ Life Satisfaction, Trust, and Participation.&lt;/a&gt;” Journal of Computer-Mediated Communication 14, no. 4 (2009): 875–901.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/02/17/is-social-media-making-us-antisocial.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/02/17/is-social-media-making-us-antisocial.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Bag Trashed By Airport Staff</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I travelled from Melbourne to Portland (Oregon), a trip that I have done many, many times before. And like many times before, it was clear that my checked luggage had been ‘inspected’. But I’d never had it inspected like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normally one is informed of a bag inspection because there’s a note from the TSA saying that one’s bag had been opened and inspected. In the past, this has been the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; way I’d known my bag was inspected, because usually the contents had been nicely replaced the way they had been found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve begun to start packing an ‘arrival bag’ in my checked luggage, which is everything I expect that I’ll need once I land after twenty-something hours of travel with extreme jet-lag. It has a couple of changes of clothes, toiletries, pajamas, chargers, a book or two, and anything else I think I might need in the first couple of days after arrival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when I opened my bag upon arriving in Portland, everything in my arrival bag had been removed, and was strewn around my suitcase. My spare shoes had been removed from their plastic bag, so they could sully my other clothes. My books, underwear, and shirts were floating freely. My cables were out and tangled with the rest of my possessions..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My socks had been unpaired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All of them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who the hell unpairs socks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s the thing, I don’t know. This &lt;em&gt;didn’t&lt;/em&gt; come with a note from the TSA, although if I were leaving someone else’s possessions in that state, I wouldn’t leave a note either. I didn’t inspect my bag between arriving in LAX and continuing on to Portland, so I don’t know if it was rummaged through before or after I entered the USA. Combined with discovering that one &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gizmodo.com.au/2012/02/australian-airports-to-get-compulsory-body-scans/&quot;&gt;can’t opt out of body-scanners in Australia&lt;/a&gt; I’m feeling that air travel comes with an even greater violation of privacy than I had previously come to expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, nothing had gone missing, but to be honest I don’t keep a manifest of my possessions when travelling. Then again I’m not usually worried about airport staff stealing things, or trashing the contents of my bags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should be…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/02/14/bag-trashed-by-airport-staff.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2014/02/14/bag-trashed-by-airport-staff.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Automate Your Life With Exobrain</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Services such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifttt.com/&quot;&gt;If-This-Then-That&lt;/a&gt; (IFTTT) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://zapier.com/&quot;&gt;Zapier&lt;/a&gt; make it easy to connect apps and automate tedious tasks. However they all require you trust your personal data with a third party. Enter &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/pjf/exobrain&quot; title=&quot;Exobrain: A collection of agents which collect, classify, and act upon data&quot;&gt;Exobrain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exobrain is a free and open source framework for extending everything. It’s like IFTTT and Zapier, but you don’t have to reveal your credentials to anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, Exobrain directly supports the following services:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://beeminder.com&quot; title=&quot;Quantify your goals with Beeminder&quot;&gt;Beeminder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Email/&lt;a href=&quot;https://gmail.com/&quot;&gt;Gmail&lt;/a&gt; (via IMAP)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://foursquare.com/&quot;&gt;Foursquare&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://habitrpg.com/&quot; title=&quot;Level up your life with HabitRPG&quot;&gt;HabitRPG&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://idonethis.com/&quot; title=&quot;Measure your progress with iDoneThis&quot;&gt;iDoneThis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pushover.net/&quot; title=&quot;Pushover: Simple mobile notifications&quot;&gt;Pushover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rememberthemilk.com/&quot; title=&quot;RememberTheMilk task tracker&quot;&gt;RememberTheMilk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Beeminder users, Exobrain also supports call-backs. This means you can chain events off anything that Beeminder can measure, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.withings.com/en/scales/&quot;&gt;Withings&lt;/a&gt; scales, &lt;a href=&quot;http://runkeeper.com/&quot;&gt;Runkeeper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fitbit.com/&quot;&gt;fitbit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rescuetime.com/&quot;&gt;RescueTime&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.duolingo.com/&quot;&gt;duolingo&lt;/a&gt;, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a quantified-selfer, you can automatically record your activities to your log. If you need some extra motivation, you can automatically gain experience points on &lt;a href=&quot;https://habitrpg.com/&quot;&gt;HabitRPG&lt;/a&gt; for achieving your goals. You can back-up all of your activity from third-party websites in real-time, or even allow people to add to your TODO list by tweeting at you with a &lt;code&gt;#todo&lt;/code&gt; tag!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you own a &lt;a href=&quot;https://getpebble.com/&quot;&gt;Pebble watch&lt;/a&gt; and are a Pushover user, then you can send notifications directly to your watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use pre-written Exobrain actions or you can write your own. Exobrain is completely free, open source, and extensible. Because it uses a shared message bus, you can even update components on the fly, without having to restart the whole system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exobrain is written in Perl and at its core uses an extensible, language-independent, messaging format based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://zeromq.org/&quot;&gt;0MQ&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.json.org/&quot;&gt;JSON&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing extensions for Exobrain is easy; here’s the entire code to send all tweets that mention you to your preferred notify service:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='perl'&gt;    &lt;span class='c1'&gt;#!/usr/bin/env perl&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='k'&gt;use&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;Exobrain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class='nv'&gt;$exobrain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;watch_loop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='n'&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;#39;Measurement::Tweet&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='n'&gt;filter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='k'&gt;sub &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nv'&gt;$_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;to_me&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='p'&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='k'&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class='o'&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='k'&gt;sub &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class='nv'&gt;$exobrain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;notify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;(&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='nv'&gt;$_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='n'&gt;summary&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='p'&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class='p'&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='p'&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exobrain is very much a work-in-progress, and we would love your contributions and feedback. You can find &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjf/exobrain&quot;&gt;Exobrain on github&lt;/a&gt;. Contributions to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pjf/exobrain/issues&quot;&gt;issues list&lt;/a&gt; are especially appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/02/09/automate-your-life-with-exobrain.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2014/02/09/automate-your-life-with-exobrain.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                     
	</channel>
</rss>
