<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>paul.j.fenwick</title>
		<description>Freedom Loving Scientist</description>
		<link>http://pjf.id.au</link>
		<atom:link href="http://pjf.id.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Visit OSCON Contribute 2016</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s with great delight that myself and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nayafia&quot; class=&quot;social-link&quot;&gt;@nayafia&lt;/a&gt; are hosting Contribute at OSCON this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by some of the amazing hacker lounges held at other conferences, we’re an open space
that’s dedicated to the advancement of Free and Open Source software and related communities.
While we have scheduled sessions for specific projects, we we’re a space for any and all
projects that need a space for coding, community, planning, meetings, or just plain getting together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have dedicated hosts so if you have questions about making your first contributions, want
to share skills, or just need someone to bring you coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about contribute on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://conferences.oreilly.com/oscon/open-source-us/public/schedule/detail/51586&quot;&gt;official OSCON schedule page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2016/05/18/oscon-contribute.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2016/05/18/oscon-contribute.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>An honest conversation about my mental health</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, time for another honest conversation about my mental health. For those of you new to my feed, this is something I do from time to time. Partly because it helps me, and partly because it helps de-stigmatise discussions about mental health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be long, rambly, and personal. Imagine you’re on livejournal. There’ll probably be typos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last three weeks I’ve been using a new mood-tracking app (iMood Journal), and I’ve been pretty happy with it compared to what I’ve tried in the past. I have it randomly sampling my mood throughout the day, and it means I can check my subjective experiences versus my recorded evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be reasonable to describe my long-term mental health right now as “adequate”. It’s not great, but it’s not terrible either. You’d probably not come to this assessment if you’ve interacted with me at all, because of the dual factors that socialising makes me feel better, and I will find excuses not to socialise when I’m not doing great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been spending a lot of time looking at what I’ve been doing well and poorly, so lets discuss individual factors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that I can report all manner of achievements and appointments, my natural motivation is pretty much non-existent right now. Almost everything I’m doing is achieved either through fear (public speaking is &lt;em&gt;great&lt;/em&gt; for fear), or cognitive willpower. Both natural excitement (I’m really enjoying X) and Annoyance Driven Development (I’m going to fix X) are presently absent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being motivationally challenged isn’t much fun. It’s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; easy to fall down with basic human maintenance, like maintaining a tidy work/home environment, sleep, nutrition, and exercise. I’m aware of these risks, and so I’m trying to correct for them, but doing all that using willpower and fear can be exhausting in itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;socialisation&quot;&gt;Socialisation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most difficult thing to talk about, and also the most relevant to my mental health. I’m an extrovert, and it’s &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; apparent that I perform extremely poorly without socialising. But there’s a bunch of challenges for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-know-an-intimidating-number-of-people&quot;&gt;I know an intimidating number of people.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little while ago some of you may remember me posting about Sharknado 3. I realised there’d be no way I could squeeze everyone who expressed interest into my home, nor would they likely form a cohesive social group, so instead I thought I’d be clever and arrange to watch bad movies with everyone who responded and their existing friend circles. That tab is &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; sitting open in my browser because the idea of scheduling that many folks into my life is intimidating, and so I’ve scheduled none at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. This is silly. It’s even sillier when I say “I should schedule time with X”, and then worry that I should also be scheduling time with everyone else, and then schedule time with no-one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know from years of playing “The Sims 2” that the solution to this is to throw parties, but those are intimidating because I wonder where I’d host them, how I’d make sure everyone would have a good time, and how I’d get a chance to have meaningful conversations with everyone in the limited period of time. Plus there’s motivation (see above). Mostly I rely upon other people scheduling parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;i-lack-in-consistent-recurrent-socialisations&quot;&gt;I lack in consistent, recurrent socialisations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people have folks they see regularly at work. They have partners, or family, or other individuals who they interact with on a regular basis. A lot of these interactions happen by default, they don’t need to be planned, they’re just part of everyday living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have these right now. I’ve been doing well with socialising in general, but—with the exception of housemates—it’s rare for me to have seen anyone more than twice before hopping on a flight to somewhere else in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to fix this. Because I travel so much, whenever I’m in a town I try to catch up with as many people as I can, which limits how often I see each individual one. Much more insidiously, part of me doesn’t want to try because no matter how much I want recurrent and consistent interactions, travelling will throw a spanner in the works after a few weeks regardless. There’s also a completely illogical fear of taking up too much of people’s times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;loneliness&quot;&gt;Loneliness&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When other folks aren’t around, and sometimes even when they are, it’s easy for me to feel lonely. There are lots of factors involved with this, and while I’m pleased to say that I’m managing this &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better than I have in the past, it’s still something which I need to be mindful of. Feelings of loneliness will consistently make me socially averse, but because I know what that feels like and how it develops, I’m much better at nipping it in the bud rather than turning into a hermit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;travel-fixing-everything-while-making-it-worse&quot;&gt;Travel: fixing everything while making it worse&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I honestly don’t know how to feel about travel right now. When it’s properly planned, it’s amazing. When I visited New York I got to see almost half my friends there, because I know an intimidating-yet-manageable amount of folks in the New York area. Conferences are great for meeting new people (which I love) and seeing my conference friends, who sometimes feel like the closest thing I have to consistent, recurrent socialising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel is also very easy for me, and really hard to refuse. If I’m invited to speak (with expenses paid) in London, or New York, or Austin, or Tokyo, then of course I’m going to want to say yes. And very often these result in amazing opportunities; they give me audiences and contacts. When I’m trying to change the world, travel is an amazing force multiplier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not travelling can also be problematic. If I feel I’m in a place for a long time, I can stop functioning properly altogether. Rather than having consistent, recurrent socialisations, I instead just don’t see my friends at all, partially due to the mistaken belief that I have plenty of time to catch up with them. Plus not travelling causes decay to my ties everywhere else in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel also means that no matter where I am in the world, I’m also missing someplace else. Plus distances and timezones wreck havoc with any sort of ties with other humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stories-and-role-models&quot;&gt;Stories and role-models&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know a lot of people who have the same or even a similar lifestyle to what I have, and this makes things just a little more tricky when wondering “so what do I do now?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m motivationally challenged, but great at hiding it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My ongoing happiness level over the last month has been “adequate”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I travel a lot, which makes socialising hard.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I lack good stories and role-models for this sort of thing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s no real take-away from all this, but it’s good for me to talk about it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ve read all the way to the end? You’re amazing! &amp;lt;3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/depression/2016/04/12/honest-conversation-about-mental-health.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/depression/2016/04/12/honest-conversation-about-mental-health.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>National Rick Astley Hotline Upgraded</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Some of you know I run the Australian National Rick Astley Hotline, on +61-3-8652-1453 . Today, in celebration of troublemakers everywhere, I’ve upgraded it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calling the number will &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; give you the classic Rick you’ve always loved, but &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; you can use your keypad for extra joy. I’ll let you discover all the options, and how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In celebration of the upgrade, I’ve &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; provisioned the United States National Rick Astley Hotline, on +1-760-706-RICK (+1-760-706-7425).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wish to help defray my costs, you can do so &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/_pjf&quot;&gt;via Patreon&lt;/a&gt;, but mostly I want you to share the numbers with your friends. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re welcome, internet, you’re welcome. :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2016/04/01/rick-astley-hotline-upgraded.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2016/04/01/rick-astley-hotline-upgraded.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Cure Evangelism</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Okay Internet, we need to talk about cure evangelism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you’ll have friends who aren’t doing too well. It could be their mental health. It could be their physical health. Maybe it’s social anxiety, or depression, or fatigue, or something else. Whatever it is, they’ve posted about it to social media as a way of getting support and maybe feeling a bit better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, there are correct and incorrect ways to respond to this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless they’ve specifically requested advice, the correct ways include sending love, saying you hope they feel better soon, or offering to help if they need it. Incorrect ways include telling them that they should try yoga to fix their social anxiety, dancing to fix their depression, or bathing in coconut oil to fix their computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These things &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; have worked for you, but no matter how good your intentions are, the person you’re trying to help feel better probably doesn’t &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; advice, they want support and love instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s worse, if they’ve mentioned their condition to anyone at all, they probably keep getting the &lt;em&gt;same&lt;/em&gt; advice. The advice you’ve given them is likely something they’ve already tried, or—more likely—you’ve asked them to do something which their condition &lt;em&gt;prevents&lt;/em&gt; them from doing. This sort of advice isn’t just frustrating, it’s &lt;em&gt;exhausting&lt;/em&gt;, and it makes people less likely to turn to social media for support in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So please, care about your friends, look after them, but don’t cure evangelise.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2016/03/21/cure-evangelism.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2016/03/21/cure-evangelism.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Changing The World Is Done In Small Steps</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s 4am, and I’ve been goth-clubbing with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kittylyst&quot; class=&quot;social-link&quot;&gt;@kittylyst&lt;/a&gt;, which of course meant I ended up having discussions about technologies with three-letter acronyms, and how to change the world. I have strong opinions about this, so I’m sharing them with you all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of people seem to think that very few people can change the world, but I feel that’s patently false. You change the world merely by living in it. That may be supporting the status quo (which is easy), or by rallying against it (which is more difficult). But for anyone who’s fought against how things are, it can feel like progress is impossible. It can feel that no matter how hard you try, you don’t make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s bollocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your brain is wired to appreciate &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt; rewards. Things which happen today, or tomorrow. But societal and global change happen slowly; they take years, or decades, or &lt;em&gt;generations&lt;/em&gt;. You can watch it happening, too. Between 1980 and 2010, the number of people living in extreme poverty went from 40% of the world’s population to 14%. In 2000 no country in the world had marriage equality laws; now we have twenty-two countries with same-sex marriage laws. Heck, we’re even making significant inroads on Malaria, which results in some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.givingwhatwecan.org/post/2015/12/bednets-have-prevented-450-million-cases-of-malaria/&quot; title=&quot;Bednets have prevented 450 million cases of malaria&quot;&gt;most satisfying animated maps I’ve ever seen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But none of these things have happened &lt;em&gt;quickly&lt;/em&gt;. They’ve taken decades, and often have decades more of progress behind them which you don’t see. While we very much &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; the world to change overnight, it’s very rare that this happens. Progress is hard work, and in some cases it’s frustrating and &lt;em&gt;unsatisfying&lt;/em&gt;, but it’s so absolutely and definitely possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s what you should be working towards. Not thinking about how do I change the world tomorrow, or next week, but &lt;em&gt;how do I change the rest of human existence&lt;/em&gt;. That may be amplifying the voices of others. It may be improving the lives of people you’ve never met. It may be discussing ideas which may be uncomfortable but necessary. It may be producing media to be watched by kids so that &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; children are raised in a much better society than we have today. It may be doing all of the above, and much, much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good investors know how to take a long-term view, and changing the world for the better is &lt;em&gt;very much&lt;/em&gt; an investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So please, don’t give up hope, don’t think your efforts aren’t making a difference. Play the long game, be willing to fight for an end-game you may never see during your natural lifetime, and don’t fall into the trap of thinking that you’re powerless. Because you’re not, but &lt;em&gt;thinking&lt;/em&gt; you are can cause you to shy away from doing all the good that you’re genuinely capable of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/ethics/2016/02/14/changing-the-world-is-done-in-small-steps.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/ethics/2016/02/14/changing-the-world-is-done-in-small-steps.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Win my hat at linux.conf.au 2016</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;For almost a decade, I’ve been presenting conference talks wearing a black top-hat.
Indeed, this has become one of the most recognisable parts of my stage-persona. So I’m
very pleased to say that you can win my original conference hat as part of the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://linux.conf.au/&quot;&gt;linux.conf.au&lt;/a&gt; charity raffle, raising money for &lt;a href=&quot;https://givewhereyoulive.com.au/&quot;&gt;Give Where You Live&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;right smaller&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;fancybox&quot; rel=&quot;group&quot; href=&quot;/images/tech/hat-raffle.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tech/hat-raffle.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photography by Erin Walsh&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hat comes with a beautiful note of authenticity—written by me—certifying
that it is indeed my conference hat. The hat-band, flower, and pins on my hat
all have great sentimental value to me, and are not incldued as part of the
raffle, but if you’ve attended the bioinformatics miniconfs you can probably
recover my genetic material. You should be aware the the hat has seen almost a
decade of regular use, and so also has significant signs of wear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those wondering, I’m not giving up the wearing of hats at conferences; instead
I’m replacing my hat substrate, and I’m delighted that the hat that I’ve
worn at so many &lt;a href=&quot;https://linux.conf.au/&quot;&gt;linux.conf.au&lt;/a&gt; events can be donated back to the community.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2016/02/02/win-my-hat-at-lca2016.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2016/02/02/win-my-hat-at-lca2016.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Fact Check: Will Pap Smears Still Be Covered by Medicare?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s fact checking time! Today, the claim that pap smears will no longer be free in Australia!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That claim is false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t link to the article in question here, because it’s misleading clickbait, but the claim that pap smears and other pathology services will no longer be covered by Medicare is scaremongering, or at least a pretty big stretch from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change which is happening is that pathology providers will no longer be given an &lt;em&gt;additional&lt;/em&gt; payment for bulk-billed tests. The cost of the procedure itself is still covered by Medicare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article is &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt; misleading when it claims that “Medicare rebates for pathology and diagnostic imaging services haven’t increased for over a decade, and now they are being cut”. The incentive payment which is being cut was introduced in 2009-2010 (much less than ten years ago) to encourage providers to bulk-bill, and was a payment to providers &lt;em&gt;in addition&lt;/em&gt; to that provided by Medicare. However since its introduction there’s been only a small increase in bulk-billing (1-3%), but a relatively large cost in incentive payments (about $1.3b over five years). It’s this additional payment that is being cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The incentive payments which are being cut range from $1.60–$4.00 per test, although additional incentives for are provided for children, concession card holders, and services in certain regional areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response it’s conceivable that some pathology providers may choose not to no longer bulk-bill for pap smears, and if those providers charge more than the Medicare rebate then patients will see out-of-pocket costs; a situation which we already see with some GPs and specialists. However we still expect to see plenty of practices continuing to bulk-bill, because bulk-billing is extremely popular with patients and guarantees a larger customer base. I would speculate that bulk-billed pap smears will still be easy to obtain, as in 2014-15 a whopping 98.7% of out-of-hospital pathology services were at no cost to the patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For detailed, primary information about the changes, you can read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aph.gov.au/About_Parliament/Parliamentary_Departments/Parliamentary_Library/FlagPost/2015/December/Changes_to_bulk_billing_incentives&quot;&gt;Australian Parliament post on the subject&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much thanks goes to Kat McGee and Daniel Reeders who did the original research, and Linda Kirkman for bringing it to my attention. I’ve just double-checked the facts, made a graphic on Facebook, and put them into my own words.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2016/01/06/will-pap-smears-no-longer-be-free.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2016/01/06/will-pap-smears-no-longer-be-free.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Best of Paul Fenwick 2015</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone! I give talks, write articles, and frequently share my thoughts and opinions. Here I’ve tried to summarise my “best of” output for 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;writing&quot;&gt;Writing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do a lot of writing about technology, mental health, society, and the future. Here are some selected pieces from this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/02/15/why-non-code-contributions-matter.html&quot;&gt;Why non-code contributions matter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/08/04/how-will-humans-remain-relevant.html&quot;&gt;Human relevance in the age of machines&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/11/16/buzzconf-was-awesome.html&quot;&gt;Buzzconf was awesome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/12/22/spacex-lands-rocket-duck-yes.html&quot;&gt;Duck yes! SpaceX lands Falcon 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/personal/2015/12/25/just-love-each-other.html&quot;&gt;Just love each other&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/depression/2015/09/06/its-time-we-spoke-about-loneliness.html&quot;&gt;It’s time we spoke about loneliness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pjf.id.au/ethics/2015/08/20/im-donating-10pc-of-my-income-to-charity.html&quot;&gt;I’m donating 10% of my income to causes that do the most good&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;videos&quot;&gt;Videos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’ve appeared at a number of conferences in 2015, not all of my talks have been taped. However I’m &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; pleased with the ones that have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xuK6udkbyGo&quot;&gt;Open Source and Social Change, Making the World a Better Place&lt;/a&gt; (20 minutes OSCON keynote)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c7TwbTtofLo&quot;&gt;The Future is Awesome (machine ethics and emerging technologies)&lt;/a&gt; (10 minute OSCON keynote)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0op6Wucdv7E&quot;&gt;The Future is Awesome (machine ethics and emerging technologies)&lt;/a&gt; (40 minute in-depth &lt;a href=&quot;https://plug.org.au/&quot; title=&quot;Perth Linux Users Group&quot;&gt;PLUG&lt;/a&gt; talk)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;audio&quot;&gt;Audio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep wanting to record more audio, but it’s something I need to have sufficient time for and be in the right mood:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X7mMvPmF-Vw&quot;&gt;The Night Watch, by James Mickens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;facebook-long-posts&quot;&gt;Facebook long-posts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also written a number of longer Facebook posts that haven’t made
it to the rest of the internet yet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/paul.fenwick/posts/10152755099264611&quot;&gt;The humanity of kicking a robot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/paul.fenwick/posts/10153256633354611&quot;&gt;Seven tips for starting a healthy community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/paul.fenwick/posts/10153293671144611&quot;&gt;Technological unemployment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/paul.fenwick/posts/10153376018579611&quot;&gt;Code is like sausages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/paul.fenwick/posts/10153398786134611&quot;&gt;Numbers in Japanese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;support-me-on-patreon&quot;&gt;Support me on Patreon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything I do is released under free licenses; indeed, everything linked to by this post is released under a &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/&quot; title=&quot;Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License&quot;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution&lt;/a&gt; license. I also don’t run ads anywhere. If you want to support my role as a thinker and opinion-writer, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/_pjf&quot;&gt;do so on Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wishing you all the best for 2016!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Paul&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2015/12/29/best-of-pjf-2015.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2015/12/29/best-of-pjf-2015.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Just Love Each Other</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen an &lt;a href=&quot;http://polyamorydiaries.com/im-madly-in-love-with-you-but-dont-worry-its-not-a-big-deal/&quot; title=&quot;I'm madly in love with you, but don't worry, it's not a big deal&quot;&gt;article on love doing the rounds&lt;/a&gt; recently, and I’m really glad to see this. People fall in love all the time, but society keeps telling us there’s only one type of love that counts, and we have an unhealthy societal expectation that we shouldn’t tell people that we love them unless they are “the one”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even without having studied relational psychology, it’s not hard to see that we’re using one word for many different things. Sternberg¹ splits love into three components: “Intimacy” (closeness, connectedness), “Passion” (physical attraction, sex), and “Dedication” (cognition, planning, commitment). A lot of long-term relationships end up having intimacy and dedication, and we call that love. A lot of friendships have the same, but many people hesitate to say “I love you” to their friends. And heaven forbid that you say “I love you” to someone you’re actually having passionate relations with, in case they’re not &lt;em&gt;the one&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as importantly, we’re seen a new wave of discussions that recognise that there are many types of attraction other than just sexual attraction. The Asexual Visibility and Education Network wiki lists at least &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asexuality.org/wiki/index.php?title=Attraction&quot; title=&quot;AVEN Wiki on attraction&quot;&gt;four types of attraction&lt;/a&gt;: sexual, romantic, sensual, and aesthetic. Attraction is not a single axis-scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Society teaches so many things about relationships which aren’t healthy. It denies that people feel different kinds of love, different kinds of attraction, and may feel these towards many people at once. We broadly define things as being “right” or “wrong” based upon expectations that relationships should fall into well defined categories: partner, friend, colleague, family member. These well-defined relationships come with well-defined behaviours that are acceptable and unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is bollocks. So much friggin’ bollocks. As a society we’re stopping people from telling their friends that they’re loved. We have expectations that if someone is in love they &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; want to have sex. We struggle with people having multiple romantic or sexual relationships, and when we do accept people with multiple relations we &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; seem obsessed into classifying those into boxes. And don’t even get me started on sexuality, slut shaming, kink, and gender roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sick of this. Not all humans, and not all human relationships fall into neat boxes. They’re dynamic, complex, messy, and &lt;em&gt;fucking beautiful&lt;/em&gt;, and society be damned if your relationships don’t fall into the scripts you’ve been taught from childhood. Don’t let someone else tell you that your relationships have to be monogamous or non-monogamous, sexual or asexual, romantic or aromantic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, do all the things I struggle to do. They’re hard, I know, because I’m worried I might be taken the wrong way, because I’m terrified that I’ll be stigmatised, because I’ve been taught that relationships &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; fall into neat categories. Talk to each other. Talk about the relationships you have. Talk about the relationships you’d &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; to have. Tell your friends that you love them. Encourage healthy relationships, &lt;em&gt;no matter what their form&lt;/em&gt;, no matter how suitable or unsuitable you feel they’d be for you personally. Enter relationships not with the expectations of society or the sub-culture in which you’ve been most influenced, but with the expectation that you’ll communicate about how you feel, and you’ll do that with honesty and respect. Follow a relationship path not because it’s what’s expected of you, but instead because it’s something you passionately want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;¹ Sternberg, R.J. “A Triangular Theory of Love.” Psychological Review 93, no. 2 (1986): 119.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cover image &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.torange.us/Holidays/valentines-day/Inscription-I-love-you-17591.html&quot;&gt;CC-BY-4.0 T-Orange&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/personal/2015/12/25/just-love-each-other.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/personal/2015/12/25/just-love-each-other.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                    

			<item>
				<title>Duck Yes! SpaceX lands their Falcon 9!</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;DUCK YES! SpaceX landed their first Falcon 9 today after it successfully deployed its payload to orbit. This is big news, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/AndyWeirAuthor/photos/a.463868883712409.1073741828.462962073803090/834802823285678/&quot;&gt;to quote Andy Weir&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Imagine if you took a flight from New York to London. And then, when you were done, they threw the plane away. Want to go back? Well, they’ll have to make a new plane. Imagine what air travel tickets would cost if the airline industry worked that way. Well, that’s exactly how the space industry works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Or at least, that’s how it &lt;em&gt;used&lt;/em&gt; to work. Until today. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy’s pretty good at explanations, but at this point at least one of you would be thinking “but what about the Space Shuttle? That was reusable!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you’re right, the orbiter was reusable, that was its primary role. The boosters were reusable, they were dropped in the atmosphere and had parachutes, but they’d land in the ocean and require a bunch of cleaning up first. The external tank was not reusable, it was jettisoned in space and would break up in the atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Space Shuttle was also breathtakingly expensive. It cost $450 million to $1.5 billion dollars &lt;em&gt;per launch&lt;/em&gt;. The system from SpaceX, the Falcon 9, costs a mere $61.2 million per launch, and it has a comparable payload to the Space Shuttle.. In terms of putting things into space, it’s cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s why a successful Falcon 9 landing is such a huge step-forward. It’s a system that can return itself from orbit and land on a pad &lt;em&gt;by itself&lt;/em&gt;. Rather than having to build a new rocket &lt;em&gt;every time&lt;/em&gt;, or clean and test something that’s landed in the ocean (salt-water is not good for spacecraft), you instead have something you can test, service, and re-use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that it’s just the first (lower) stage which is able to self-land at the moment. The second stage (which delivers the payload) isn’t re-usable yet, but that’s the next step, and I’m quite certain we’ll see it self-landing before long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having both stages be able to land themselves means we’d see that $61.2m launch cost drop to an estimated $5–7m, which is pretty friggin’ amazing. It could be even less; the cost of fuel is only 0.3% of the vehicle costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really can’t express how amazed I am by this. We’d be looking at being able to do HUNDREDS of launches for the same price as a single Space Shuttle launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bravo, SpaceX, you rock!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/1B6oiLNyKKI?html5=1&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1B6oiLNyKKI&quot;&gt;Watch on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/12/22/spacex-lands-rocket-duck-yes.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://pjf.id.au/tech/2015/12/22/spacex-lands-rocket-duck-yes.html</guid>
			</item>
		

                    
                    
                     
	</channel>
</rss>
